--==本字幕由 HDWinG字幕组 荣誉出品==--
翻译制作：CK@HDWinG
HDWinG字幕组作品   转载请注明出处
本字幕仅供学习交流  严禁用作任何商业盈利行为
他来了
He is coming.
快找掩护
Cover your butt.
找什么？
Cover the what?
巫师维特鲁威
Vitruvius.
邪恶暴君
Lord Business.
老家伙  你把克拉格藏得佷好嘛
You've hidden the Kragle well, old man.
克拉格：一管被擦去标签的万能胶  亦指片中使用的万能胶品牌
小的们  杀了他
Robots, destroy him!
是  商业之王
Yes, Lord Business.
你的机器人是敌不过我的建筑大师的
Your robots are no match for a MasterBuilder.
因为我能洞穿万物
For I see everything!
额  我的眼睛
Unh! My eyes! Ow!
世界上最强的武器  克拉格
The Kragle. The most powerful super weapon...
现在是我的了
...is mine.
太好了  克拉格是我的了
Oh, the Kragle!
现在我的邪恶力量将永无止尽  你们感受到了吗
Now my evil power will be unlimited! Can you feel me?
我们感受到了
I can feel you.
现在没有什么东西能阻止我了
Whoo! Nothing's gonna stop me now.
慢着  曾经有一则预言
Wait. There was a prophecy.
什么时候又来了个预言了
Oh, now there's a prophecy.
是关于反抗法宝的
About the Piece of Resistance.
哦  是吗  传说中充满魔力的反抗法宝
Oh, yes! The supposed missing Piece of Resistance...
可以使克拉格失效
...that can somehow magically disarm the Kragle.
你饶了我吧
Give me a break!
总有一天  会有一个才华横溢的天才少年
One day, a talented lass or fellow
一个拥有黄色皮肤的救世主
A Special One with face of yellow
会在地底的洞穴中
Will make the Piece of Resistance found
找到反抗法宝
from its hiding refuge underground
并且带领着宏伟的军队
And with a noble army at the helm
这个建筑大师将会阻止克拉格并且拯救这个世界
This MasterBuilder will thwart The Kragle and save the realm
他将成为有史以来最伟大  最风趣
And be the greatest most interesting
并且最重要的人物
most important person of all times
这些都是真的
All of this is true
因为这则预言读起来押韵
Because it rhymes
天呐
Oh, wow.
你编的这个故事  还真是伟大而又振奋人心的传奇啊
That was a great, inspiring legend that you made up.
一个救世主？
A "Special One"?
真是异想天开  满口胡言
What a bunch of hippie-dippie baloney.
八年半后
早安  我的公寓
Good morning, apartment!
早安  门道  早安  墙壁
Good morning, doorway! Good morning, wall.
早安  天花板  早安  地板
Good morning, ceiling. Good morning, floor!
准备好开始新的一天了
Ready to start the day!
找到了
Ah, here it is!
《社交指南》  如何如人相处
"Instructions to fit in...
让大家都喜欢你
...have everybody like you...
并一直保持开心
...and always be happy!
第1步：
Step one:
深呼吸
Breathe."
好了  完成第1步
Okay, got that one down.
第2步：迎接新的一天  并微笑着说
Step two: Greet the day, smile and say..."
早安  亲爱的城市
Good morning, city!
-早安  亲爱的城市    -早安  亲爱的城市
- Good morning, city!   - Good morning, city!
-早安  亲爱的城市    -早上好  亲爱的城市
- Good morning, city!   - Top of the morning to you there, city!
-早安  亲爱的城市  你好吗    -早上好  亲爱的城市
- Good morning, city! How you doing?   - Good morning, city!
第3步：锻炼
Step three: Exercise."
跳爆竹  搞定它
Jumping jacks. Hit them!
跳爆竹：一种跳跃运动  可以调节和协调身体
One!
Two!
Three!
我好兴奋啊
I am so pumped up!
第四步：淋浴
Step four: Shower."
永远记得让你的眼睛远离肥皂
And always be sure to keep the soap out of your--! Aah!
第5步：刮胡子
Shave your face.
第6步：刷牙
Brush your teeth.
第7步：梳头
Comb your hair. Hmm.
第8步：穿衣服
"Wear clothes."
差点忘了这个
Oop! I almost forgot that one!
不  不  不
No. No. Uh-uh. No.
错了  不是这件
Not that. Wrong.
就是这件了  大功告成
And that's it. Check.
第9步：和所有你生命中重要的人
Step nine: Eat a complete breakfast...
一起吃顿丰盛的早餐
...with all the special people in your life.
嘿  小树  你今早准备干吗？
Hey, Plantie, what do you wanna do this morning?
看电视？  我也是
Watch TV? Me too!
嗨  大家好  我是你们的总统商业之王
Hi, I'm President Business...
奥坦公司的董事长和全世界的统治者
president of the Octan Corporation and the world.
奥坦公司：一个虚构的加油站品牌  经常出现在各种主题中
我们一定要按照《指导手册》来办事  否则你们就要被安乐死
Let's take extra care to follow the instructions, or you'll be put to sleep.
另外  别忘了"墨西哥卷饼星期二"就在下周哦
And don't forget Taco Tuesday's coming next week!
所有遵守规则的公民都可以在那一天得到免费的墨西哥卷饼和我的祝福
That's the day every rule-following citizen gets a free taco and my love!
祝大家拥有愉快的一天
Have a great day, everybody!
祝你也拥有愉快的一天  总统先生
You have a great day too, President Business.
天呐  他真是太酷了  我总是想多听到他的声音
Man, he's such a cool guy. I always wanna hear more of what--
等等  他刚才说"安乐死"？
Wait, did he say "put to sleep"?
今晚的《我的裤子在哪里》即将播出
Tonight on Where Are My Pants?
亲爱的  我的裤子在哪里
Honey, where are my pants?
我刚刚在想什么？  我不在乎
What was I just thinking? I don't care.
第11步：和你的邻居打招呼
Step 11: Greet your neighbors."
-嗨  乔    -嗨  兄弟
- Hey, Joe.   - Hey, pal.
注意点  嗨  冲浪者戴夫
Whoa! Hey, Surfer Dave.
嗨  兄弟
Hey, brah.
-早上好  雪莉    -早上好  伙计
- Oh, good morning, Sherrie.   - Hey, fella.
-嘿  贾丝敏  德克斯特
- Oh, hey, Jasmine, Dexter.
安琪  洛基  坏勒罗伊
Angie, Loki, Bad Leroy.
毛茸茸的  毛茸茸二号  毛茸茸三号
Fluffy, Fluffy Junior, Fluffy Senior.
杰夫
Jeff.
第12步：准守所有的交通标志和规则
Step 12: Obey all traffic signs and regulations.
第13步：享受流行音乐
Step 13: Enjoy popular music.
本期排行榜的榜单冠军又是
Top of the charts again...
-《一切妙不可言》    -哦  我的天哪  我爱死这首歌了
-...it's "Everything ls Awesome."   -Oh, my gosh, I love this song!
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
一切是如此美好
Everything is cool
当你成为团队的一部分
When you're part of a team
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
当我们实现
When we're living our
梦想
Dream
永远记得使用方向灯
Always use a turn signal.
车子要停在分道线之间  搞定
Park between the lines. Yes!
把干洗的物品在中午之前送过去
Drop off dry-cleaning before noon.
读读新闻头版头条
Read the headlines.
别忘了要保持微笑
Don't forget to smile.
永远支持当地的运动队
Always root for the local sports team.
冲啊  运动队
Go, Sports Team!
永远要记得回应别人的赞扬
Always return a compliment.
-嘿  你看上去气色佷好    -你也是
- Hey, you look nice.   - So do you!
喝昂贵的咖啡
Drink overpriced coffee.
你点的咖啡好了  总共37美元
Here you go. That's $37.
太好了
Awesome!
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
你昨晚看《我的裤子在哪里》了吗
Did you see Where Are My Pants? last night?
"亲爱的  我的裤子在哪里"
"Honey, where's my pants?"
经典的剧情
Classic episode.
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
总部来的指令
Instructions coming in from Central.
好了  总部说如果你们见到什么奇异的事物就炸了它们
Okay, it says here to take everything weird and blow it up.
好了  各位
All right, Cylinderheads...
让我们把它做的和指令的一样吧
...let's make it look like it does in the instructions!
嘿  朋友们
Hey, buddy!
我需要一个1×2的积木
I need a 1-by-2 key hole.
没问题  迈克尔
No problem, Michael.
我们需要一个2×2的零件
We need a 2-by-2 macaroni.
-2×2的零件来了   -这有一个
- 2-by-2 macaroni flying in.   - Here's one.
各位  有一个1×1的缩进了螺柱一侧
Guys, got a 1-by-1 with an indented stud on one side.
-大家加油    -收到  罗杰
- Cheese slopes. Come on, everybody.   - Roger that, Roger.
快点  说你呢
Look alive, coming at you.
我这里需要跟多的积木
Can I get a couple LURPs over here?
-多谢  盖尔    -朋友们  看我把这拆了
- Thanks, Gail.   - Guys, watch me drill this down.
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
当你成为团队的一部分  一切都是如此美好
Everything is cool When you're part of a team
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
我在监视着你们
当我们实现梦想
When we're living our dream
你听说了吗？  每个人都在讨论呢
Have you heard the news? Everyone's talkin'
生活是美好的  因为一切妙不可言
Life is good Because everything's awesome
天呐  我现在的感觉真好  我可以连续几个小时唱这首歌
Man, I feel so good right now! I could sing this song for hours!
五小时后
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
当我们实现梦想
When we're living our dream
当你身处集体之中
When you're part of a team!
耶
Yeah!
今晚下班后  我准备去体育酒吧
I'm going to the sports bar after work tonight.
谁想要去吃美味的鸡翅  好好的疯一把吗
Who wants to eat some delicious chicken wings and get crazy?
鸡翅  我爱死鸡翅了
Chicken wings? I love chicken wings!
嘿  有谁想要和我一起分享这羊角面包吗
Hey, who wants to share a croissant with this guy?
羊角面包  我爱死羊角面包了
Croissants? I love croissants.
太好了  我爱死大香肠了
Oh, yeah! I sure do love giant sausages.
大香肠  不是吧
Giant sausages? No way!
你知道我喜欢干什么吗
You know what I love to do?
是和我生命中重要的人一起进餐
Is share a meal with the special people in my life.
佛瑞德  巴里  盖尔  我  还是你？
Fred, Barry, Gail, me and you?
啊  不  等等我  伙计们
Ah! No, wait, guys!
别飞走  好吧  我们待会在体育酒吧会面
Wait up! Okay, I'll meet you there.
哦  它飞哪去了
Oh. Where did it go?
好吧  你在这啊
Oh, there you are.
我好像听到什么东西飞过去的声音
I think I heard a whoosh.
宝物探测中
找到宝物
嘿  朋友  虽然我很讨厌这么说
Hey, pal, I hate to tell you this...
但是  我觉得这不是你该呆的地方
...but, uh, I don't think you're supposed to be here.
《指导手册》中明确规定
Yeah, the rules specifically state...
工作场所六点关闭  并且这是必须带安全帽的区域
...work site closes at 6, it's a hard-hat area only.
你的穿着不是正规的安全橙色
That's not official safety orange.
"如果你看到什么奇怪的事情  立马禀报"
"If you see anything weird, report it immediately."
既然这样  那我想我得
Well, I guess I'm gonna...
要举报你了
...have to report youuu...
小姐  你要去哪  我并没有打算吓你的  我...
Where are you going? Miss! I didn't mean to scare you! I'm sor--
嘿  看来也不是很糟糕嘛
Hey! Heh. That's not so bad.
那是什么
What is that?
过来
Come here.
我该怎么做  我把《指导手册》搞丢了
What do I do? I don't have my instructions.
伸手来触摸我
Touch the Piece.
伸手来触摸我  伸手来触摸我
Touch the Piece. Touch the Piece.
我感觉也许我应该过去触摸它
I feel like maybe I should touch that.
这真是太
It's so...
有趣了
. . . interesting.
伸手来触摸我
Touch the Piece.
这真是太有趣了
It's so interesting.
伸手来触摸我
Touch the Piece.
触摸
Touch the--
一个拥有黄皮肤的救世主
A Special One with face of yellow
将会在地底的洞穴中
Will make the Piece of Resistance found
找到反抗法宝
From its hiding refuge underground
发生什么事了
What's going on down here?
这个建筑大师将会阻止克拉格并且拯救这个世界
This MasterBuilder will thwart The Kragle and save the realm
快点  埃米特
Come on, Emmet!
救世主已经诞生
The Special has arisen.
轮到你当英雄了
It's your turn to be the hero.
醒醒
Wake up.
快点醒过来
Come on, wake up!
建筑大师在哪
Where are the MasterBuilders?
你怎么找到反抗法宝的
How did you find the Piece of Resistance? Eh?
-其他的藏在哪？    -早安  我的公寓
- Where are the others hiding?   - Good morning, apartment?
醒醒
Wake up!
你是怎么找到反抗法宝的
How did you find the Piece of Resistance?
什么的法宝？
The piece of what?
反抗法宝
The Piece of Resistance.
我...我不...我这是在哪？  发生什么事了
I-- I don't-- Where am I? What's happening?
"发生什么事了？"
"What's happening?"
跟我装聋作哑吗  建筑大师
Playing dumb, MasterBuilder.
不  我... 建筑大师？
No. I-- "MasterBuilder"?
-你是想告诉我你从来没有听说过预言    -是的
- Oh. So you've never heard of the prophecy?    - No.
或者救世主
Or The Special?
没有
No, no!
你这个骗子  我们会杀了你
You're a liar! We'll kill you!
听着  我在电视上看到过很多警匪片
Look, urn, I watch a lot of cop shows on TV.
不是应该还有...
Isn't there supposed to also be--?
不是应该还有个好警察吗
Isn't there supposed to be a good cop?
是的  但我们的帐还没算完呢
Oh, yes. But we're not done yet.
嗨  朋友  我是你友好的邻里警察
Hi, buddy! I'm your friendly neighborhood police officer!
-想要喝杯茶吗    -还真想喝
- Would you like a glass of water?   - Yeah. Yeah, actually.
真遗憾  你喝不到了
Too bad.
安全摄像头拍下了这个
Security cameras picked up this.
你在建筑工地被发现的时候  正背着一块奇怪的东西抽搐
Unh! You were found at the construction site convulsing with a strange piece.
真是太恶心了
That's disgusting!
那它为什么牢固的粘在了你的背上
Then why is it permanently stuck to your back?
把它从我背上拿下来  把它从我背上拿下来
Get it off me! Get it off me!
它掉不下来  它粘在我身上了
It won't come off! It's chasing me!
听着  这不是我的错
Look, it's not my fault!
我也不知道这东西怎么会粘到了我的背上
I have no idea how this thing got on my back!
朋友  我当然相信你
Of course, buddy. I believe you.
太好了
Great.
我也相信你
I "believe" you too.
用两种不同的口气说  是因为之前说应该有好坏两个警察的缘故
你看到我用爪形手做的手势了吗
You see the quotations I'm making with my claw hands?
这意味着我并不相信你
It means I don't believe you!
为什么偏偏就在总统大人
Why else would you show up with that thing on your back...
准备用克拉格来毁灭这个世界的前三天
...just three days before President Business...
这个东西就出现在你的背上
...is going to use the Kragle to end the world?
总统大人准备毁灭这个世界？
President Business is gonna end the world?
但他是个很好的人啊
But he's such a good guy.
还有奥坦公司  他们总是能做出好东西
And Octan, they make good stuff.
音乐  乳酪产品  咖啡  电视节目
Music, dairy products, coffee, TV shows...
监控系统  历史书  投票机
...surveillance systems, all history books, voting machines.
等等
Wait a minute.
你不会真的这么愚蠢吧
Come on, you can't be this stupid.
这是个误会
This is a misunderstanding.
我只是个平凡的普通人
I'm just a regular, normal, ordinary guy.
并且我已经要迟到了  我得去见我最好的朋友
I'm late to meet my best friends in the whole world.
他们现在可能已经在想我了
They're probably missing me right now.
他们可能已经在外面四处找我了
They're probably out looking around.
"嘿  埃米特在哪里？  我最好的朋友埃米特在哪里？"
"Hey, where's Emmet? Hey, where's my best friend Emmet?"
你知道吗  你可以去问我所有的朋友  他们会告诉你的
Hey, you know what? Ask all my friends. They'll tell you.
哦  我们已经问过他们了
Oh, we asked them, all right.
埃米特啊  他不像是个犯罪首脑
That guy's not a criminal mastermind.
看到没
See?
他就是个平平常常的普通人
Yeah. You know, he's kind of an average, normal kind of guy.
谢谢
Thank you.
但是  你知道吗  他不是
But, you know, he's not, like...
他的平凡和我们不一样
...normal like us. No.
他没有那么特别
He's not that special.
等等  我有点困惑  我们到底在说谁
Wait, I'm so confused. Who are we talking about?
他和我们一起工作吗
Wait, does he work with us?
盖尔不记得我了？
Gail doesn't remember me?
比如说兰迪
Look at Randy here.
他喜欢香肠  这是他的特色
He likes sausage. That's something.
盖尔很活泼  这是她的特色
Gail is perky. That's something.
还有哈利
And Harry...
当你说起哈利的时候  我会捧腹大笑
When you say Harry, I go: Haaa
当你说其他人的时候  我就
When you say the other guy, I go:
哈利是最棒的
Harry's the best!
-哈利很有个性    -他很古怪  他很古怪
- Harry's got personality.   - He's weird! He's weird!
我知道埃米特  但是也仅此而已
I know that guy but I know, like, zippy-zap about him.
我们早上还刚谈论过
We just talked earlier.
我的意思是  他只会说是的
I mean, all he does is say yes...
附和其他人
...to everything everybody else is doing.
他就是有点...
You know, he's just sort of a "Hmm!"
有点白痴吧  我认为
Little bit of a blank slate, I guess.
总共是42美元
That'll be $42, please.
我们都有自己的特色  但是埃米特
We all have something that makes us something and Emmet is...
一无是处
...nothing.
你看到了
There you go.
我跟你说我就是个普通的小人物
I told you I was a nobody.
这是最完美的掩饰
It's the perfect cover.
掩饰？  掩饰什么？
Cover? Cover for what?
我从他这得不到什么信息  把他带到熔化室去
I can't break him. Take him to the melting chamber.
什么？
What?
你要熔化了我？  我会死吗？
You're gonna melt me'? Am I gonna die?
你会活着  你会活得好好的
You'll live. You'll be fine.
总统先生  他现在就在我手里
President Business. I have him right here, sir.
是的  我告诉他他会活下去  所以他没有逃跑  但是...
Yes, we've told him he'll live so he doesn't try to escape, but, um...
我们是在骗他而已
...we're lying to him.
等等  你刚说什么
Wait, what did he just say?
别动
Hold still.
等等  这肯定是搞错了  你们抓错人了
Wait! There's obviously been a mix-up here. You've got the wrong--
这很快就会开始疼了
That is gonna start hurting pretty soon.
不  不  不要
No, no, no!
你是谁
Whoa. Who are you?
是你啊
It's you?
如果你不想死的话  就跟我走吧
Come with me if you wanna not die.
嗨  各位  熔化的怎么样了
Hi, everybody! How's the melting goi--?
嘿  嘿  嘿
Hey, hey, hey”
红色警报  红色警报
Red alert, red alert.
所有人都过来  我再说一遍  所有人都给我去追救世主
I need everyone, repeat: everyone, to go after The Special.
隧道在这个个方向
The tunnel's that way.
哦  天呐
Oh, boy!
先生  你真是太有才了
Oh, sir, you're brilliant.
我们要建造个摩托车冲出去
We'll build a motorcycle out of the alleyway.
还不知道你的名字呢
So, uh, didn't catch your name...
或者你准备做什么
...or anything about what you're, uh, up to.
或者我们在这干什么
Or what we're doing here.
先生  把你自己装成是个无用的小人物  这个做法真是太聪明了
It's brilliant, sir, that you pretended to be a useless nobody...
但你也可以跟我一起坐摩托战车  没事的
...but you can drop the act with me. It's cool.
哦  摩托战车
Oh, the act.
跳上来  我们出发吧
Jump on. Let's go!
-嘿  我    -抓紧了  先生
- Hey, uh, I--   - Hang on, sir.
所有单位
All units...
截住他们  现在
...cut him off on Elm, now!
或者你可以的时候
Or whenever you can.
10-4  坏警察
10-4, Bad Cop.
-小心    -抓紧了
- Watch out!   - Hold on.
我们需要去和维特鲁威会和
We need to meet up with Vitruvius...
并且告诉他法宝已经找到了
...and tell him the Piece has been found.
他们在单轨铁路上面
They're up on the monorail.
派出直升机
Release the copper choppers.
哦  不
Oh, no!
你能告诉我发生什么事情了吗
Will you please tell me what is happening?
我在营救你  先生  你是预言提到的那个人
I'm rescuing you, sir. You're the one the prophecy spoke of.
你是救世主
You're The Special.
我？
Me?
你找到了反抗法宝
You found the Piece of Resistance.
而且预言中说
And the prophecy states...
你是这个世界最重要  最才华横溢
...that you are the most important, most talented...
最风趣
...most interesting...
和最杰出的人
...and most extraordinary person in the universe.
那说的就是你  对吗？
That's you. Right?
是的  就是我
Uh, yes. That's me.
太好了  你来开
Great. You drive.
什么
What?
我想回家
I wanna go home!
我不是说这个
This is not what I meant!
哦  不
Oh, no.
小心  救世主
Look out, Special!
抱歉  第一次驾驶摩托车 对不起
Uh, sorry. Never driven a motorcycle. Sorry!
他太神奇了
Wow, he's amazing.
真是难以置信
That was incredible!
你简直比预言中说的还好
You're even better than the prophecy said you'd be.
真的吗
Oh. Really?
我是...我是温斯黛
I'm, uh-- I'm Wyldstyle.
-哦  对不起  你说什么    -温斯黛
- Oh, I'm sorry, what was it?   - Wyldstyle.
-温斯黛    -是的
- "Wyldstyle"?   - Yep.
-你做什么的  DJ吗？    -不是
- What are you, a DJ?   - No.
DJ是指从事电台广播剧、电视台新闻报道等电子媒体节目播音工作的人
-哦  那是你的名字啊  温斯黛    -是的
- Oh, that's your name? "Wyldstyle"?   - Yeah.
就像你的出生证明上  写着温斯黛
Like on your birth certificate, it says "Wyldstyle."
我们还是不要讨论我的名字了
Let's not talk about my name!
别让救世主跑了
Don't let The Special get away.
长官  我们已经封锁了高速公路
Sir, we've blocked the freeway.
抓紧了
Hang on, sir!
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
让我们飞起来吧
Let's fly!
飞向秘密通道
Head for the secret tunnel.
额  这里是城市禁区
Uh, these are the city limits.
我们飞向通道就好了
Let's just head for the tunnel.
你想让我开进那奇怪的涡旋形的洞？
You want me to drive into that weird swirly hole?
你疯了吗
Are you insane?
不要刹车  冲  不要停下来  冲啊
Don't brake! Go! Don't stop! Go! Now!
我做不到
I can't do this!
这是违反规定的
That is against the instructions!
等等  你最喜欢的餐馆是哪个
Wait, what's your favorite restaurant?
阿尼连锁餐馆
Any chain restaurant.
最喜欢的电视节目
Favorite TV show?
《我的裤子在哪里》
Where Are My Pants?
最喜欢的歌
Favorite song?
一切妙不可言
Everything ls Awesome
哦  不
Oh, no!
等等  我们在哪
Wait. Where are we?
旧西部
这真是太奇怪了
This is so weir--!
你不是救世主  你骗我
You're not The Special! You lied to me!
这真的得看情况
It really kind of depends on--
你甚至不是个建造大师  对吧
You're not even a MasterBuilder, are you?
额  我的意思是  我知道什么是建造大师
Uh, I mean, I know what a MasterBuilder is.
不如你告诉我建造大师是干嘛的  那样的话我就知道你是不是对的
Why don't you tell me what it is? That way I could see if you're right.
你毁了预言
You've ruined the prophecy.
听着  我很抱歉  只是...
Look, I'm sorry, okay? You just--
被人当成救世主的感觉很好
You made being special sound so good.
我还以为可以一直跟你到达世界的尽头
And to think I was going to follow you to the end of the universe.
真的？
You were?
是这样的
Here's the thing.
我们怎么就能确定我不是救世主呢
How do we know for sure that I'm not The Special?
-我们还不确定呢    -安静
- We just don't know it yet.   - Quiet.
你们想要巨大的火鸡腿吗
Y'all want a giant turkey leg?
你知道这东西会对你的结肠造成什么影响吗
Do you have any idea what that does to your colon?
-哦  我的天呐    -把这帽子戴上
- Oh, my G-O-S-H.   - Just put the hat on.
还有这个  这个  这个
...and this. And this. And this.
和这个
And this.
顺带说一句  我有男朋友了
And, by the way, I have a boyfriend.
额  我不太明白你为什么要说这个
Uh, I'm not sure exactly why you'd bring that up.
这事情很严重
It's super serious.
你不会想要招惹他的
You do not want to mess with him.
好吧
Okay
所以  别打我的主意了
So don't get any ideas.
我从来没有过什么想法
I never have any ideas.
等等
Wait!
-把他们吊起来    -把手放到我看得到的地方
- Stick them up.   - Hands where I can see them.
嘿  听着  你可以解释下为什么我要穿成这样吗
Hey, uh, listen. You think you can explain why I'm dressed like this...
还有天上这个大大的词是怎么回事
...and what those big words in the sky were all about?
还有  我们处在什么年代
And, like, where we are in time.
你家  砖块城堡  只是宇宙中许多领域中的一个
Your home, Bricksburg, is one of many realms in the universe.
还有这一个
There's also this one...
海盗湾  骑士俱乐部  维京人  小丑镇
...Pirate's Cove, Knight's Club, Viking's Landing, Clown Town...
以及很多我们没必要提及的地方
...a bunch of others we don't need to mention.
邪恶暴君  或者你认为的
Lord Business, or as you think you know him...
总统先生
...President Business...
偷了克拉格  这个世界上最强大的武器
...stole the Kragle, the most powerful object in the universe.
等等...
Blah, blah, blah.
正确的名字  地名以及一些其他的事情
Proper name. Place name. Backstory stuff.
反抗法宝  救世主
...Piece of Resistance is The Special.
我很漂亮  我喜欢你
I'm so pretty. I like you.
但由于一些原因  我很生你的气
But I'm angry with you for some reason.
...宇宙的尽头...
...tower at the end of the universe...
把反抗法宝放到克拉格之上
...put the Piece of Resistance onto the Kragle...
就能永久的消灭它
...and disarm it forever.
太好了
Great.
我觉得我已经明白了
I think I got it...
但为了以防万一
...but just in case...
你把所有的事情再给我说一遍  我刚才没听
...tell me the whole thing again. I wasn't listening.
好吧  曾经这个世界上的人们  可以
Okay. All the people of the universe were once free to travel...
随意往来他们想去的地方
...and mingle and build whatever they wanted.
但邪恶暴君看不惯这样的混乱
But President Business was confused by all the chaos.
所以他在不同的领域间建立起了墙来阻隔
So he erected walls between the worlds...
并逐渐沉迷于秩序和完美
...and became obsessed with order and perfection.
然后他偷了神秘的
And he stole the mysterious...
超强武器——克拉格
...secret super weapon called-- The Kragle!
并且雇佣坏警察
and he hired Bad Cop...
来追杀所有的建筑大师  一群善于创造和改变的人
...to hunt down all the MasterBuilders, who were always changing everything.
我们剩下的人
And those of us who remained...
消身匿迹的躲了起来  并且建造了神秘隧道
...well, we went into hiding. Built the tunnels to survive.
我们一直在找寻反抗法宝
And we search for the Piece of Resistance.
唯一一件可以阻止克拉格的法宝
The only thing that can stop the Kragle.
克拉格  我知道这个
Kragle. I know that.
抓我的那个警察  他曾经说过一些关于克拉格的事
It might have been that cop. He said something about the Kragle.
邪恶暴君准备用克拉格
President Business was going to use the Kragle...
在三天后毁灭世界
...to end the world in three days.
我完全不明白什么意思
I can't make any sense of it.
墨西哥卷饼星期二
Taco Tuesday.
我就知道那很可疑  我们没时间浪费了
I knew that was suspicious. There's no time to lose.
我们必须找到维特鲁威  然后赶去奥坦大厦
We must find Vitruvius and get to the Office Tower before it's too late.
好吧
Okay
一个人的办公室能有什么可怕的
Heh. How scary can someone's office be?
总统大人  我们在尝试追踪逃犯
President Business, we're trying to locate the fugitive...
但是它的面孔实在太普通了  能和我们数据库中的每一个人匹配
...but his face is so generic it matches every other face in our database.
恶毒的
Diabolical.
好的  让坏警察在23秒内
Okay, have Bad Cop meet me in my office...
-到我的办公见我  恰奥    -好的  长官
-...in 23 seconds. Ciao.   - Will do, sir.
咖啡销售已经再创新高  先生
Coffee sales are through the roof, sir.
很好  让我们把屋顶建得再高点
Glad to hear it. Let's rebuild that roof to be even higher!
屋顶团队已经在施工了
The roof team is on it.
长官  这张给墨西哥卷饼星期二的海报可以吗
Sir, can you approve this poster for Taco Tuesday?
完美
Perfect.
-我爱这间房间里的所有人    -我们也爱你  先生
- I love everyone in this room.   - We love you, sir!
-无线电台的工作做得很好    -多谢夸奖
- Great job on the radio station.   - Thank you, sir.
我们喜欢一遍又一遍的听着这首歌
We love listening to this song over and over again.
保持下去  伙计们
Keep it up, GUYS-
亲爱的  我的裤子在哪里
Honey, where are my pants?
停
Cut!
令人捧腹大笑  这永远也不会过时
Hilarious. That never gets old.
确实不会
It does not.
坏警察已经在您办公室等您了
Bad Cop is waiting for you in your office.
太好了
Wonderful. Fantastic.
你可以取消我2点的安排吗
Would you cancel my 2:00?
接下来这个会议可能会有点
This next meeting could run a little bit...
血腥
...deadly.
激活头盔
Activate helmet.
灯光启动中
Light sequence.
火焰测试
Flame test.
大门开启
Engage dramatic entrance.
坏警察
Bad Cop.
商业之王  我知道救世主跑了  但是
Lord Business. I know The Special got away, but--
别这么紧张嘛
Don't be so serious.
另外一个警察呢
Where's the other guy?
-嘿  朋友    -嘿  伙计
- Hey, friend.   - Hey, buddy!
-我想你了    -真的吗
- I missed you.   - Aw, did you really?
我给你展示过我的宝物收藏吗
Have I ever shown you my relic collection?
没有
Nope. I don't think you have.
没人知道这些东西哪来的
Nobody knows where this stuff comes from.
这一件
This one...
是一个创口贴
...is the Cloak of Ban Da'ld.
我听说想要将它从身上撕下来是很痛苦的
I hear it's super painful to take off.
-你要试试吗？    -这个...
- You wanna try it on?   - Well, um--
不用的  但是谢谢你
No, but thank you.
坏警察  过去几年我们一起做了很多了不起的事情
We've done some great work over the years together, Bad Cop...
抓捕这些建筑大师
...capturing all those MasterBuilders...
折磨他们  等等
...and torturing them and whatnot.
多谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
但是
Although...
你确实让反抗法宝被带走了
...you did let the Piece of Resistance go.
唯一一件可能会毁了我计划的东西
The one thing that can ruin my plans.
唯一一件我让你多加注意的东西
The one thing that I asked you to take care of.
这让我很是懊恼
That's super frustrating.
让我想要随便抓起任何一个
It makes me just wanna pick up whoever...
离我近的人
...is standing closest to me...
然后把他从这个窗户扔出去
...and throw them through this window...
丢进无尽深渊之中
...and out into the infinite abyss of nothingness!
我特别想这么做
I wanna do it so bad.
长官  我知道你想这么做  但我请求你不要
I know you do, sir. Please don't.
坏警察  不只是你一个人不断破坏我的计划
And it's not just you, Bad Cop, that keeps messing up my plans.
到处都有人在反抗我
People everywhere are always messing with my stuff.
但我有自己的解决方式
But I have a way to fix that.
一个让事情不超出我控制方式
A way to keep things exactly the way they are supposed to be.
永远的保持
Permanently.
看好了
Behold...
所有宝物中
...the most powerful weapon...
最强大的武器
...of all the relics:
克拉格
The Kragle!
正如你所见到的  他们正在把克拉格装到一个巨型机器中
As you can see, they're loading the Kragle in a big machine upstairs.
我把它称作
I call it...
克拉格触手喷射器
...the Tentacle Arm Kragle Outside Sprayer.
或者是TAKOS
Or TAKOS.
S代表的是寂静
The "S" is silent.
所以在墨西哥卷饼星期二的时候
So on Taco Tuesday...
它将会把克拉格喷射向所有人和物
...it's going to spray the Kragle over everyone and everything...
通过像这个一样的超级喷嘴
...with a bunch of super-scary nozzles like this one!
-我来给你演示下它是怎么工作的    -长官  我看这就不必了吧
- I'll show you how it works.   - Sir, I don't know if this is necessary.
哦  不要担心  我不会在你身上做实验的
Oh, don't worry. I won't test it on you.
我会拿你父母来试验
I'll do it on your parents!
什么？
What?
-嗨  儿子    -嗨
- Hi, son.   - Hi!
你在这座大城市过得怎么样
How's it going in the big city?
妈妈  爸爸  你们来这干嘛啊
Mommy. Daddy. What are you doing here?
好的  爸爸  我只要你像平时一样就可以了
Okay, Pa. I just want you to act naturally.
-就像你平时在家里一样    -好的
- Like you're going about your day.   - Gotcha.
对  把你的手就像这样举起来
Yeah. Keep your hand up like that.
妈妈
Ma, scoot...
往你右边走两步
...two steps in to the right.
爸爸  每次我和妈妈说话的时候
Pa, whenever I talk to Ma...
-你就得开始动起来    -对不起  先生
-...you start to move.   - Sorry, sir.
退回你原来的位置
Get back to where you were!
-这里？    -对
- Here?   - Perfect.
太好了  你做的非常好  你没事就别动了
That's great. You can't do anything better. No reason why you should move.
好的
Right.
现在  妈妈
Now, Ma...
把你的手放到他的肩上   然后你
...hand on his shoulder. And you--
爸爸  你刚刚又动了  都被你给毁了
Pa, you just moved and you've just wrecked it!
你毁了这个游戏
You wrecked it!
坏警察  你明白我的要求是什么了吗
Bad Cop, you see what I'm talking about?
我要求的是绝对的完美
All I'm asking for is total perfection.
叫机器经理进来
Send in a Micro-manager!
自动造型程序启动
Commencing micro-management.
你们站着别动
Hold still, you guys.
然后
And then...
我只需要用TAKOS喷射器
...I just spray them...
把克拉格喷射出来
...With the TAKOS.
哦  孩子他爸  抓紧我
Oh, Pa, hold me.
哦  亲爱的  我的腿动不了
Oh, darling, I can't move me legs.
坏警察  这让你很心烦吗？
Does that upset you, Bad Cop?
你肯定为你父母感到难过  你想要帮他们  对吧？
Surely you feel bad for your parents, and you wanna help them, don't you?
儿子  我们没事  只是有点卡住了
We're okay, son. Just a little stuck, is all.
继续
Go ahead...
完成工作
...finish the job.
没问题  长官
Of course, sir.
不  我不想做
No, I don't want to.
-你必须去做    -我不想做
- You have to.   - I don't want to.
-你就不能安静点吗    -我做不到
- Would you please be quiet?   - I can't.
-你必须这么做  闭嘴    -但是他们
- You must. Shut it!    - But they--
-这样做不好    -这是你的工作
-It's not nice.   -It's your job, man.
我不能这么做
I can't do it.
-他们是无辜的    -和我想的一样
- They're innocent.   - Just as I thought.
坏警察  你好警察的一面让你变得心软了
Your Good Cop side's making you soft, Bad Cop.
小的们
Robots!
给我把棉签
Bring me the fleece-crested Scepter of Q-Teep...
和清洁剂拿过来
...and the Pé-Lish Remover of Na-ll.
你已经让救世主跑过一次了
You've already let The Special get away once.
长官
Sir.
我现在必须确保同样的事情不会再发生
I'm just gonna make sure it doesn't happen again.
好警察  你从此消失吧
No more Mr. Nice Guy!
不  我的儿子
Oh, son!
在墨西哥卷饼星期二  我将把整个宇宙都粘住
On Taco Tuesday, I'm going to Kragleize the entire universe...
这样大家就会停止对我的反叛
...so that everyone will stop messing with my stuff!
你是选择和我一起
Are you gonna be with me...
还是和你父母一起
...or are you gonna be stuck...
粘在这里喝茶聊天
...having a tea party with your mom and dad?
儿子
Son?
对不起了  爸爸
Sorry, Dad.
我还有工作去做
I have a job to do.
你只需要融入这里
All you have to do is blend in and act like you belong here.
太好了
Ah, perfect.
你好  我是个牛仔
Well, hi there, I'm a cowboy!
啪  啪  啪...
Bang, bang, bang-bang-bang-bang!
射  射  射  子弹  子弹  枪
Shoot, shoot, shoot. Bullet, bullet, gun.
咝  咝  咝
Zap, zap, zap, pow. Zap, pow.
胡言乱语中
-他们在看什么    -我之前说错了
- What are they looking at?   - I made a mistake.
你应该站着别动  就像个板凳似的
You should just be still. Act like a stool.
-等等    -你们好  各位
- Wait!   - Howdy, guys!
-安静  板凳是不会说话的    -来做到我身上
- Quiet. Nope, stools don't talk.   - Come sit on me.
好了  安静
Okay, shh.
让我来示范一遍给你看
Let me show you how it's done.
多好的以为女士啊
What a lady!
好了  我们去找到找到巫师
Okay, let me just find the wizard...
然后解决了这件事
...and get this over with.
他在这儿
There he is.
-维特鲁威    -谁？
- Vitruvius.   - Who?
我从没听说过这个人  我也不是这个人
I've never heard of that man, whom I am not.
-你是哪位？    -是我啊
- Who are you?   -It's me.
我是一个看不见的盲人
I am a blind man and cannot see.
我是温斯黛
It's Wyldstyle.
你是一个DJ吗
Are you a DJ?
-什么？  为什么每个人都...    -等等
- What? Why does everybody--?   - Oh, wait, wait.
你是我过去那个缺乏安全感
Are you the student I used to have...
经常换名字的学生吗
...who was so insecure she kept changing her name?
不  不  我不是
No, no, no.
-先是暗黑风暴  接着又换成杰米尼兹    -我从来没有做个这种事
- First Darkstorm, then Geminizzle.   - No. Never.
然后是永不微笑  畸形脸  时髦裤衩
Then Neversmile, then Freakface, then Snazzypants.
好吧  我承认  我是的
Okay. All right, yes.
10秒后在楼上和我会面
Meet me upstairs in 10 seconds.
10秒后
哦  天呐
Oh, man.
你有个非常奇怪的
You have a very weirdly...
-装饰屋    -多谢夸奖
-...decorated place.   - Thank you.
维特鲁威  我们找到反抗法宝了
Vitruvius, we have found the Piece of Resistance.
-这是真的吗    -是的  但是
- Is it true?   - Yes, but--
温斯黛  预言说
Wyldstyle. The prophecy states that...
你就是救世主
...you are The Special.
善良的化身  恶魔的克星
The embodiment of good, foiler of evil.
这个世界上最具天赋  最才华横溢
The most talented, most brilliant...
以及最重要的人
...most important person in the universe.
如果是那样就太好了
That would be great...
但是埃米特才是那个找到反抗法宝的人
...but Emmet is the one who found the Piece.
哦  好的  埃米特
Oh, okay. Emmet!
预言说
The prophecy states that...
你就是救世主
...you are The Special.
-最具天赋    -我不确定他是不是救世主
- The most talented--   - I'm not sure he's The Special.
因为他连建筑大师都不是  看着
Because he's not even a MasterBuilder. Watch.
埃米特  利用你周围的这些东西
Emmet, just given what's around you...
-造些简单的东西出来    -好的
-...build something simple.   - Okay.
-比如一辆和酷的跑车    -好的
- Like an awesome race car.   - Great.
-开始吧    -你有建筑指南吗
- Go.    - Do you have the instructions?
不  我的君主  你必须在你的大脑中自己创建规则
No. You must create the instructions in your mind, my liege.
哦  好的  跑车啊
Ah. Okay. Race car.
这里真的有好多很酷的东西
Well, there's a lot of really cool stuff here.
没有看到车轮
Don't see a wheel...
或者
...Or...
多三个轮子
...three more wheels.
看到没  他做不了  他永远也成不了建筑大师
See? He can't do it. He will never be a MasterBuilder.
如果你一直告诉他他做不了  他当然不行
Of course not. Not if you keep telling him he can't.
他必须明白他能做到
He needs to see that he can.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
-我们要进入你的脑海    -什么
- We are entering your mind...   - What?
去证明你拥有着尚未发掘的潜力
...to prove that you have the unlocked potential...
让你成为一个建筑大师
...to be a MasterBuilder.
酷  我们现在是在我大脑中吗
Whoa, are we inside my brain right now?
真大  我肯定很聪明
It's big. I must be smart.
因为有人认为脑袋大的就聪明
这里面好像没有什么活力
I'm not hearing a lot of activity here.
我认为他从来没有过自己独到的思想
I don't think he's ever had an original thought. In his life.
哈哈  这你就说错了
Ha, ha. That's not true.
比如说  我有一次想要
For instance, one time I wanted to have...
一群朋友来我这看电视
...a bunch of my friends over to watch TV--
但不是这个像魔法一样突然出现的电视
Not unlike this TV that just showed up magically.
我的沙发容不下这么多人
And not everybody can fit on my one couch...
然后我就想
...and I thought to myself:
"如果能有个东西像双层床一样拥有两层
"What if there was such a thing as a bunk bed...
但是仍然是个沙发"
...but as a couch?"
像你们隆重介绍双层沙发
Introducing the double-decker couch.
因此所有的好朋友都可以一起看电视
So everyone could watch TV together and be buddies!
这简直是我听说过的最蠢的事情了
That is literally the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
别说了  温斯黛  让我来
Please, Wyldstyle, let me handle this.
这个想法真是太差了
That idea is just the worst.
这附近肯定有些东西
There must be something around here...
可以证明他的潜力
...that proves his potential.
如果上帝选中他作为救世主
If The Man Upstairs chose him to be The Special...
肯定是有原因的
...there must be a reason.
-谁是上帝？    -听到没？
- Who's The Man Upstairs?   - See?
他甚至不知道上帝
He doesn't even know about The Man Upstairs.
他是不是有一双特别粗野的手
Does he have, like, super-gross hands...
看上去就像是粉红色香肠做的
...that look like they're made out of big pink sausages?
像鹰的爪子和鱿鱼的混合吗?
Like eagle talons mixed with squid?
等等  你见过...
Wait. You've seen the--?
那是我刚刚在想的东西
That's what I was just thinking about.
你怎么...
How did you--?
当我触摸到法宝的时候  我就有了这个奇怪的梦
I had this weird dream when I touched the Piece.
好吧  其实我没睡着  所以这也称不上是个梦
Well, I mean, I wasn't asleep, so it wasn't really a dream.
埃米特  你梦见上帝了
Emmet, you had a vision.
真的吗
I did?
建筑大师们花费多年的时间
MasterBuilders spend years...
去训练自己来清空他们的大脑
...training themselves to clear their minds enough...
只为了拥有一睹上帝真容的机会
...to have even a fleeting glimpse of The Man Upstairs...
然而  你的大脑本身就是空的
...and yet, your mind is already so prodigiously empty...
压根就没什么需要清除的东西
...that there is nothing in it to clear away in the first place.
只要有正确的训练
With proper training...
你就能成为一个伟大的建筑大师
...you could become a great MasterBuilder.
我可以吗？
I could?
埃米特  预言选中了你
The prophecy chose you, Emmet.
但我并没有拥有做不了任何预言中
But I can't do any of the stuff...
说我拥有的能力
...that the prophecy says I'm supposed to do.
你只需要相信自己
All you have to do is to believe.
然后
Then...
你就可以洞穿万物
...you will see everything.
你准备好了吗  我的孩子
Are you ready, my son?
我准备好了
Yes, I am.
我觉得
I think.
那我们就没有时间去浪费了
Then we haven't a moment to lose.
我们必须召集
We must assemble...
建筑大师们
...the MasterBuilders.
你觉得飞船是个不好的发明吗
Do you think Zeppelins are a bad investment?
你们中有人见过这个人吗
Any of you fellas seen this guy?
等等  伙伴
Wait a minute, partner.
在他头上画个牛仔帽
Draw a cowboy hat on him.
这些机械鸟会把我们的消息送出去
These mechanical birds will get our message out.
他们会去网络咖啡屋
They will go to an Internet cafe...
然后给剩余的建筑大师发邮件
...and e-mail the remaining MasterBuilders...
然后他们会和我们在秘密的领域梦幻之境中会和
...who will meet us in the secret realm of Cloud Cuckooland.
梦幻之境？  等等  那之前说的训练呢
Cuckooland? Wait. What happened to that whole training part?
别担心  埃米特
Don't worry, Emmet.
你的训练现在就开始
Your training begins now.
钢琴师
Piano man...
快开门
open up-
你的训练晚点开始
Your training begins later!
倒数三下
On three.
One--
-我觉得我们安全了    -别动  暴徒们
- Whew. I think we're in the clear.   - Freeze, turkeys.
我只想要反抗法宝
All I want is the Piece of Resistance.
我们宁愿他死了也不会给你的
We would rather he died than give it to you.
我不会想要他死的
I would not rather he died.
听着  各位  我们可以心平气和的解决这件事  或者我们...
Look, everybody, we can do this the easy way, or we can do it--
快跑
Go, run!
看来他们选择了暴力的方式  开火
They took the hard way. Fire!
开火
Fire!
维特鲁威  去梦幻之镜该往哪走
Vitruvius, which way to Cloud Cuckooland?
朝着空中又大又亮的东西走
Head for the big bright thing in the sky.
-你是指太阳？    -是的  就是它
- You mean the sun?   - Yeah. Yeah, that's it.
让我们离开这里  用这个
Let's get out of here. Here, use this.
什么？  等等
What? Wait, hey--
-你在干嘛呢？    -出发
- What are you doing? Aah!   - Let's go!
我不知道我到底在干吗
I don't know what I'm doing.
再见
Good bye.
嘭
Boom!
哦  不
Oh, dang!
我被猪围住了  我讨厌猪
Aah! I've got pigs! I hate pigs!
不要在这里胡来了  我需要你帮忙
Quit playing around in the mud. I could use your help.
温斯黛  我们真的需要
Wyldstyle, we could really use...
你帮忙
...your help!
维特鲁威  他们追上来了  快做点什么
Vitruvius, they're gaining on us. Build something!
让埃米特试试
Let Emmet try!
不要  我们还是别让埃米特试了  我还没有接受过任何训练呢
No, let's not let Emmet try! I haven't had any training.
没事的
That's okay.
我们就从怎么成为建筑大师开始
We'll start with how to become a MasterBuilder.
第1步：相信你的直觉
Step one: Trust your instincts.
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay. Um--
造出点什么  造出点什么东西啊
Build something! Build something!
尝尝这个
Aha. Take that!
除非你的直觉很糟糕
Unless your instincts are terrible.
不  车轮
No! The wheel!
我支持不了太久了
I can't control it much longer!
埃米特  我们需要把轮子加到能旋转的东西上
Emmet, we need to attach the wheel to something that spins around.
我们需要把轮子加到能旋转的东西上
We need to attach the wheel to something that spins around.
能旋转的东西  旋转  旋转
Something that spins around. Spins around. Spins around.
知道了
Oh.
埃米特  你要去哪
Emmet, where are you going?
这最好能成
Oh, this better work.
抓紧了
Hang tight!
救命啊
Dagnabit!
干得好  埃米特
Well done, Emmet.
嘿  我成功了
Hey! I did it.
你真的做到了
Wow. You actually did it.
火车
Train!
哦  不
Oh, no.
从我的火车上下去
Get off my train.
快跑
Run!
温斯黛
Wyldstyle!
好痛
Owie!
他要撞到我们了
He's gonna ram us.
快  快  快  那一块  给我那个积木
Quick, quick, quick! That piece! Give me that piece.
嗯？
Huh?
建个斜坡
Build a ramp!
搞什么鬼
What the heck?
去死吧
Rest in pieces.
哦  不
Oh, no.
等等  不  不  不
Wait. No, no, no.
嘿
Hey
多谢你刚才救了我
Thanks for saving my life back there.
虽然  你知道的
Even if, you know...
最终被证明那是毫无意义的
...eventually it turned out to be pointless.
无论如何
Well, for what it's worth...
这都将是我生命中最精彩的15分钟
...this has been about the greatest 15 minutes of my life.
怎么...
What the--?
各位  放轻松  我在这呢
Relax, everybody, I'm here.
蝙蝠侠
Batman!
-你好啊  亲爱的    -亲爱的
- What's up, babe?   - Babe!
-什么？    -哦  对不起  蝙蝠侠  这是埃米特
- What?   - Oh, sorry. Batman, this is Emmet.
埃米特  这是我的男朋友蝙蝠侠
Emmet, this is my boyfriend, Batman.
我是蝙蝠侠
I'm Batman.
这是你男朋友？
That's your boyfriend?
蝙蝠侠  你们在哪认识的
Batman, huh? Where'd you guys meet?
那是个很有趣的故事  对吧  小蝙蝠
It's actually a funny story, right, Bat?
在那呢
There he is.
-很高心见到你  坏警察    -蝙蝠侠
-"Police" to meet you, Bad Cop.   - Batman!
这真是
The pleasure...
荣幸之至
...is all "spine."
你知道吗
Guess what...
你这个大傻瓜
...you big dumb baby.
你的车就跟婴儿车似的
Your car is a baby carriage.
哦  不  你的男朋友不见了
Oh, no, your boyfriend's gone.
-嘿  亲爱的    -什么？
- Hey, babe.   - What?
让我们手牵手
Let's hold hands.
额
So, uh...
嘿  各位  我觉得我们要撞进太阳了
Hey, guys, I think we're about to crash into the sun.
是的  这将会变的很酷的
Yeah, but it's gonna look really cool.
这就是梦幻之境吗  我没有看到什么云彩
Uh, is this Cloud Cuckooland? I don't see any clouds.
-或者杜鹃鸟啊    -不  不  这是
- Or cuckoos.   - No, no, this is...
新西兰中部
...Middle Zealand.
一个奇妙的大陆
A wondrous land...
这里充满了骑士  城堡  羊肉
...full of knights, castles, mutton...
刑具  贫困、水蛭、文盲
...torture weapons, poverty, leeches, illiteracy...
还有
...and, um...
龙
Dragon!
对  也有龙
Yeah, that too.
一旦我们到达梦幻之境  我们将会组织起
Once we arrive at Cloud Cuckooland, we'll raise an army...
一只建筑大师的军队
...of MasterBuilders to--
无论如何  你们一定得看看我新安装的低音喇叭
Anyway, you guys gotta check out these new subwoofers I installed.
我把它们叫做野狗  听他们狂吠吧
I call them the dogs. Listen to them bark!
你能把这声音调低点吗
Can you turn that down a little bit?
这首歌是我写给温斯黛的
This is a song I wrote for Wyldstyle.
黑暗
Darkness
这是一首关于我是个孤儿的歌
It's about how I'm an orphan.
无父无母
No parents
这才是真正的音乐 埃米特
This is real music, Emmet.
蝙蝠侠是个真正的艺术家  黑暗  沉思
Batman's a true artist. Dark, brooding.
我也会黑暗和沉思啊
Well, I'm dark and brooding too.
各位  快看  有彩虹
Guys, look, a rainbow.
所以你会开上彩虹
So you're gonna drive up the curved part...
超级富豪
Super rich
沿着彩虹直到最高点
...take it all the way to the top...
让他变得更好
Kind of makes it better
然后把车停在那
...and park the car.
朋友们  欢迎来到梦幻之境  现在
Friends, welcome to Cloud Cuckooland. Now...
我只需要打开秘密大门
I just need to give the secret knock.
好吧
Okay
我只是跟你们来了
I'm just gonna come right out.
但我完全不知道到底发生了什么  或者这是什么地方
I have no idea what's going on, or what this place is at all.
嗨  我是独角猫公主
Hi! I am Princess Unikitty...
欢迎你们来到梦幻之境
...and I welcome you all to Cloud Cuckooland.
事先根本毫无征兆
There's no signs or anything.
你们怎么知道什么不该做
How does anyone know what not to do?
这就是梦幻之境
Here in Cloud Cuckooland...
这里没有规则
...there are no rules.
没有政府
There's no government...
没有保姆
...no babysitters...
没有就寝时间
...no bedtimes...
没有忧郁的脸庞
...no frowny faces...
没有不修边幅的人
...no bushy mustaches...
也没有任何消极情绪
...and no negativity of any kind.
你刚都说了上千遍"没有"了
You just said the word "no" like a thousand times.
也不需要前后如一
And there's also no consistency.
我讨厌这个地方
I hate this place.
任何主意都是好的
Any idea is a good idea...
除了不高兴的主意
...except the not happy ones.
那些你深埋心底的主意
Those you push down deep inside...
你永远  永远  永远
...where you'll never, ever, ever...
永远
...ever...
也不会找到它们
...find them.
你们的建筑大师已经在汪星人大厅集结了
Your fellow MasterBuilders are gathered in the Dog.
什么？
The what?
呃  那是超人吗
Ah! Is that Superman?
姑娘  在做什么呢
Girl, what are you doing?
-嘿  超人    -哦  嘿  怎么了
- Hey, Superman!   - Oh, hey. What's up?
-我是绿灯侠    -我知道了
- Lantern. Green Lantern.   - Yeah, yeah.
开会的时候想坐在一起吗
You wanna sit together at the meeting?
额  我必须回氪星去
Um, I have to go back to Krypton.
氪星不是已经毁了吗
Didn't Krypton blow up?
我的建筑大师们  包括但不限于以下几位：
My fellow MasterBuilders, including but not limited to...
罗宾汉  美人鱼
...Robin Hood, Mermaid Lady...
甘道夫
...Gandalf...
沼泽半兽人
...Swamp Creature...
-80年代的太空人   -你好
-...1980-something Space Guy...   - Hello!
2002年的NBA全明星
...2002 NBA All-Stars...
还有神奇女侠
and Wonder Woman.
你们从大老远跑来  只为了这历史性的一刻
You have traveled far to be here for a moment of great import.
我们已经获悉
We have learned...
邪恶暴君打算启用
...that Lord Business plans to unleash...
完全状态的克拉格
...a fully weaponized Kragle...
在墨西哥卷饼星期二那天
...on Taco Tuesday...
来毁灭这个世界  正如大家以前所了解的一样
...to end the world as we know it.
请各位保持冷静
Please, calm yourselves.
绿忍者
Green Ninja...
米尔豪斯
...Milhouse...
仁慈的吸血鬼
...Nice Vampire...
米开朗基罗  忍者神龟
...Michelangelo, Michelangelo...
还有克利欧佩特拉
...and Cleopatra.
我们还有希望
There is yet one hope.
救世主已经诞生
The Special has arisen.
让这个年轻人上前来
Have the young man step forward.
如你所愿  大布利多
As you wish, Dubbledore.
邓布利多：哈利波特中霍格沃茨魔法学校校长  也是个巫师
我是甘道夫
I'm Gandalf!
-那应该读成邓布利多    -大布利多
-It's pronounced "Dumbledore."   - Dubbadore?
不是  是邓布利多
No, "Dumbledore."
你不就是说"大布利多"吗
Thought you said "Dubbadore."
维特鲁威
Vitruvius!
你得把你名字写下来  因为我是没打算去记它的
You gotta write that down. I'm not gonna remember any of it.
好了  我们开始吧
But here we go.
现在救世主要给大家做个演讲
The Special will now give an eloquent speech.
上来吧  你能行的
Go ahead, man. You got this.
好吧
Okay
大家好  我是埃米特
Hello. I'm Emmet.
还有  这就是反抗法宝
Oh, and this is the Piece of Resistance.
多谢
Thank you.
额  我很高兴
Well, uh, I know that I, for one...
能与你们一起合作
...am very excited to work with you guys...
进入奥坦塔  找到克拉格
...to get into the Octan Tower, find the Kragle...
然后把这反抗法宝放到克拉格上
...and put this thing on the thing.
我知道这会是十分艰难的  但是
And I know it's going to be really hard, but--
十分艰难？
"Really hard"?
用你的钩子手来擦屁股才叫困难
Wiping ye burn with a hook for a hand is really hard.
这是完全不可能
This be impossible.
上次我们尝试攻击邪恶暴君办公室时
The last time we tried to storm Lord Business' office...
我们用了所有我们能设想到的计划
...we used every plan we could conceive.
但结果却是令人难以启齿的惨败
The result was a massacre too terrible to speak of.
你是哪位？
Who are you?
我叫金属胡子
The name be Metal Beard.
而且我会告诉你我的苦衷
And I'll tell you me tale of woe.
这下好了  他又来说了
Oh, great, here we go again.
我来到
I arrived...
奥坦塔的脚下
...at the foot of the Tower...
和我齐心协力的建筑大师们
...with me hearty MasterBuilder crew...
却发现克拉格在塔的最高层
...only to find the Kragle was all the way up on the infinityeth floor...
被一群机器人军队保卫着
guarded by a robot army...
而且安保措施考虑了
...and security measures...
各种可能发生的
...of every kind...
进攻方式
...imaginable:
激光
Lasers...
鲨鱼
...sharks...
武装了激光的鲨鱼
...laser sharks...
傲慢的助理
...overbearing assistants...
还有各种奇怪、危险的法宝
...and strange, dangerous relics...
比如创口贴
...that entrap...
订书机
II-Snap...
还有电池
...and zap.
还有个叫做思维牢笼的神秘房间
And there be a mysterious room called the Think Tank.
我想尽了各种办法才
I barely made it out of that...
从把我的头颅
...room...
和各种器官
...with just me head!
那个房间逃出来
And organs.
好吧
Okay
我不得不换掉身体的每一部分
I had to replace every part of my once-strapping...
来造就我这气概十足的海盗身材
...virile pirate body...
用的就是你现在看到的这些垃圾
...with this useless hunk of garbage ye see before ye.
因此  如果你觉得回去那个被抛弃的奥坦塔
So if ye think it'd be a good idea to return...
是个好主意的话
...to that forsaken place...
救世主
...Special...
你能有什么比
...what idea have ye that be better...
这里的其他建筑大师们
...than the ideas of 100...
更好的方法呢
...of our fallen MasterBuilder brothers?
好吧
Well, uh...
严格说来  我还不是个建筑大师
Well, technically I'm not exactly a MasterBuilder yet.
什么？
What?
安静  各位  安静
Please! Everyone! Please!
垃圾
Rubbish!
是的  这是真的
Yes, it's true.
我或许不是个建筑大师
I may not be a MasterBuilder.
我或许没有太多的经验
I may not have a lot of experience...
来战斗、领导或着提出计划
...fighting or leading or coming up with plans.
或者给大家出主意
Or having ideas in general.
事实上  我没有那么聪明
In fact, I'm not all that smart.
而且我也不是你们说的"创造型"的
And I'm not what you'd call a "creative type."
另外
Plus...
我没有熟练的技能
...generally unskilled.
而且
Also...
非常胆小和懦弱
...scared and cowardly.
我知道你们在想什么
I know what you're thinking:
"他是这个世界上
"He is the least qualified person...
最没有资格领导我们的人"
...in the world to lead us."
你们是对的
And you are right.
你觉得这么说就能让我们好过些吗
This is supposed to make us feel better?
不  我还没有说完呢  接下来就该用"但是"转折了
No, there was about to be a "but."
-你就是个笑柄    -是的
- You're a butt!   - Yes.
此处但是(but)与笑柄(butt)同音
你们只能靠自己了
You all be on your own!
我要退出这项注定要失败的事业
I be leaving this lost cause!
你为什么要离开
Why are you leaving?
一个充满分歧的房间
A house divided against itself would be better...
都要比这好
...than this.
亚伯拉罕·林肯
Abraham Lincoln!
把你的太空飞椅飞回来
You bring your space chair right back here!
别这样  各位
Come on, guys!
我们还是可以这么做的  对吗
We can still do this. Right?
你一点也不特殊
You're not even a bit special.
你说得对  他确实是一事无成
Well, you were right about him being a ding-dong.
你带给我们的只是失望而已
You're a huge disappointment.
把他给我赶出去  我不想再看到他
Get him out of here. I don't wanna look at him.
至少情况不会变得比这更坏了
Well, at least it can't get any worse.
看来我错了
I was wrong.
我们被入侵了
It's the Orb of Tee-ti-list!
喔哦  坏人来了
Ruh-roh. It's the bad guys.
喔哦  他怎么...
Whoa. How did he--?
走  快跑  所有人保护救世主
Go! Run! Come on, everyone! Protect The Special.
他踝关节上的东西是什么
What's that on his ankle?
是一个跟踪装置
It's a tracking device.
把建筑大师们抓到监狱去
Take the MasterBuilders prisoner.
是他把入侵者引来的
Oh, he led them right to us.
各位  不  不  不  这不是我的错
Guys, no, no, no. It's not my fault.
你是我见过的最糟的领袖  快到蝙蝠战车上去
You are the worst leader I've ever seen. To the Batmobile!
该死的
Dang it.
去隐形战机那
To the invisible jet!
-该死    -大家都自保吧
- Dang it!   - Every man for himself.
不  我们必须保护反抗法宝
No, we must protect the Piece.
沙克  知道现在是什么时辰吗？
Shaq, do you know what time...
沙克·奥尼尔：NBA球星  绰号鲨鱼
-是？    -是游戏时间
-...it is?   -It's game time.
你们都准备接招吧
Y'all ready for this?
哦  不  他们是有备而来的
Oh, no! They were ready for that.
它居然没坏
It didn't break!
因为这是用克拉格粘起来的  机关枪
Because it's Kragled. Machine gum!
开火
Fire!
不
No!
啊  我动不了了
Aah! I can't move!
别担心  超人
Don't worry, Superman.
-我会把你救出来的    -不  不要
- I'll get you out of there.   - No! Don't!
哦  我的天呐  我的手粘住了  我的脚也粘住了
Aah! Oh, my gosh. My hands are stuck. My legs are stuck as well.
我恨死你了
I super hate you.
-啊  你要把我拆散架了   -亲爱的
- Ow! You're pulling my torso off.   - Babe...
快来帮我救他
...help me get him out of here.
我说了"每个人自保"
I said "every man for himself."
嘿  你得支持我
Hey, you gotta be there for me.
好吧
Fine!
好吧  好吧  好吧
Fine. Fine. Fine.
-我需要你的态度好一点    -我有一个很好的
- I need you to have a better attitude.   - I have a great...
-态度    -好痛
-...attitude.   - Ouch.
追踪中...
救世主在西北方向
The Special's in the northwest quadrant.
我们已经把他逼入绝境了
We've got him cornered.
好痛  好痛  好痛
Ouch. Ouch. Ouch.
他跑哪去了
Where'd he go?
哦  不
Oh, no!
他们击中我们的云稳定剂了
They've hit our silly cloud stabilizers!
我们走  我们得把埃米特救出去
Let's go! We need to get Emmet out of here.
-我们不能建些什么东西吗    -嘿  我是本  不过你可以叫我本尼
- Can't we build something?   - Hey! I'm Ben. But you can call me Benny.
我可以建造宇宙飞船  看好了
I can build a spaceship. Watch.
宇宙飞船  宇宙飞船  宇宙飞船...
Spaceship, spaceship, spaceship Spaceship, spaceship
不  你不能见这个  空中被包围了
No! You can't. The skies are surrounded.
没事的  反正我也没真想建
That's okay. I didn't really wanna build...
一艘宇宙飞船  没事的
...a spaceship anyway. That's cool.
我们要去哪才能不被发现
Where can we go where we can't be found?
也许我们该到水下去
Maybe we could go underwater?
要不我们去水底下吧
What if we went underwater?
好主意  亲爱的
Great idea, babe!
蝙蝠侠  多谢你  你的主意是最好的
Thank you, Batman. Your ideas are the best.
但我刚刚也说了这个
But I just said that.
-我们需要建一艘潜艇    -一艘蝙蝠潜艇
- We could build a submarine.   - A Bat-Submarine, patent pending.
要有彩虹
With rainbows!
还有睡袋，以防我们要打盹
And dream catchers, in case we take a nap.
就像个水下的宇宙飞船
Like an underwater spaceship!
但你不能一次性造这么多啊
But you can't build all of them at once.
准备好了吗  开工
Ready? Break.
好吧
Okay
蓝盆子和酸苹果
Blue razzleberry and sour apple!
如果任何人有黑色的部分  我需要它们  明白了吗
If anybody has black parts, I need them, okay?
我工作的时候只穿黑色
I only work in black.
偶尔也用非常深沉的灰色
And sometimes, very, very dark gray.
-用些黄砖    -嘿  各位  我能帮帮吗
- Use the yellow bricks!   - Hey, guys, can I help?
-不  必须这样    -不  我需要那个
- No! It has to be this way!   - No, I need that!
他在哪
Where is he?
有谁知道这是什么吗  还有你需要这个吗
Anyone know what this is, and do you need it?
我觉得我们需要用到机翼和火箭推进器
I think we could use wings and rocket boosters.
把你的东西从我的地盘拿出去
Ew. Get your retro space stuff out of my area.
各位  告诉我到底该做什么  以及如何去做
You guys, hey, just tell me exactly what to do. And how to do it.
埃米特  你不用管其他人在做什么
Emmet, don't worry about what the others are doing.
你必须发掘你自己与众不同的地方
You must embrace what is special about you!
他在那
There he is!
所有人  攻击那艘潜艇
All units, attack the sub!
埃米特  快进来
Emmet, get in here!
拦住他  拦住他  不要让他
Stop him! Stop him! Don't let him...
潜进水里
...get to the water!
俯冲  俯冲  大家都进来
Dive, dive, dive! Everybody in!
我们要下去了
We're going under!
哦  不
Oh, no.
我的家园
My home.
都毁了
It's gone.
我感觉自己体内
I feel something inside.
有一股愤怒的情绪
It's like the opposite of happiness.
我必须保持乐观
I must stay positive.
泡泡糖
Ah. Bubble gums.
蝴蝶
Butterflies.
棉花糖
Cotton candy.
天啊  我对不起你  独角猫
Gosh, I'm so sorry, Unikitty.
你想坐下来谈谈吗
Do you want to sit down and talk about it?
这鬼东西是什么
What the heck is that?
这是张双层沙发
It's a double-decker couch.
当时看起来是个很好的主意
Which seemed like a good idea at the time...
但现在我意识到它并没什么用
...but I now realize it's not super helpful.
但是  它有杯托
But, you know, it has cup holders.
座椅下面还有冷却器
Seats flip up with coolers underneath.
你还真是各方面都令人失望啊
You are so disappointing on so many levels.
为什么我的裤子又冷又湿
Why are my pants cold and wet?
船体破洞
Hull breach.
墙壁在哭泣
The walls are crying!
潜艇的缝合处正在不断瓦解
We're coming apart at the seams!
这不该是蝙蝠侠的死法
This is not how Batman dies.
埃米特
Emmet!
-抓紧了  抓紧了    -温斯黛
- Hold on, hold on!   - Wyldstyle!
大家深呼吸
Deep breath! Deep breath, everybod--!
机器经理们  下面发生什么事了
Micro-managers, what's going on down there?
扫描海底残骸
Scanning submarine wreckage.
没有发现幸存者
No survivors detected.
能潜水的警察们  如果有必要就疏通整个海洋
Scuba cops, dredge the entire ocean if you have to.
我们必须找到反抗法宝
We have got to find that Piece.
让我们押送这些囚犯回去见商业之王
Let's get these prisoners back to Lord Business...
然后把这个好消息带给他
...and give him the good news.
救世主已经不复存在了
The Special is no more.
大家好
Hello, everybody!
超人  神奇女侠  真没想到你们也会在这
Superman. Wonder Woman, I had no idea you'd be here.
沙奎尔·奥尼尔先生
Mr. Shaquille O'Neal.
沙奎尔·奥尼尔：美国篮球运动员
大家好
Greetings, all!
欢迎来到我的思想牢笼
Welcome to my Think Tank.
救救我们
Help us!
这些年你抓的建筑大师们
All the MasterBuilders you've captured over the years...
你都把他们关在这
...you've brought them here.
你是一个聪明人  超人
You're a very perceptive person, Superman.
他们想出了宇宙中一切的指令
They come up with all the instructions for everything in the universe.
小的们
Robots!
不  不
No! No!
再也找不到比这更糟的了
Can't get much worse than this.
-你好  邻居    -哦  不
- Uh, hello, neighbor.   - Oh, no.
我是绿灯侠
It's Green Lantern.
哦  我的天呐  我们现在是室友了  真是太好了
Oh, my gosh, we're roommates! How crazy is that?
有谁能够给我一些氪石吗
Does anyone have some Kryptonite that they could give me?
等等  救世主哪去了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Where is The Special?
救世主和反抗法宝沉入了海洋底下
The Special and the Piece of Resistance are at the bottom of the ocean.
等等  你是和我说你没抓到他
Wait, are you telling me you don't have him?
长官  在我们说话这会  我那些能潜水的手下正在找寻他们的残骸呢
Sir, my scuba team is looking for his remains as we speak.
坏警察  他有可能还活着  法宝可能还在那
Bad Cop, he could still be alive! The Piece could still be out there.
那个救世主唯一剩余的作品只是张双层沙发
The only remnant of The Special was a double-decker couch.
等等
Wait, hold on.
你说一张双层沙发
A double-decker couch?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
真的？  就是把上下铺变成了沙发？
Really? So it's like a bunk-bed couch? Is that what it's like?
这还真是奇怪
That's weird.
如果你坐在上层的中间
If you're sitting in the top middle...
除非你从某人身上爬过  不然该怎么下来呢
...how are you gonna get down without climbing over someone?
如果你坐在沙发的底层看电视
If you're sitting on the bottom and you're watching TV...
那你不是还得看着上层摇晃的大腿？
...are you gonna have to watch through a bunch of dangling legs?
这样还有谁愿意坐底层啊
Who's gonna want to sit on the bottom?
这还真是
It is literally...
我听说过的最没用的主意了
...the most useless idea I have ever heard.
-看吧  你还活着    -是啊
- Well, we're still alive.   - Yeah!
嘿  双层沙发
Heh. The double-decker couch.
看来也不是完全没用嘛
It wasn't totally pointless after all.
这是唯一一件没有毁了的东西
It's the one thing that stayed together.
我一直都相信你  埃米特
I always believed in you, Emmet.
我不是故意想要破坏气氛  但是是否有人注意到
I don't mean to spoil the party, but does anyone else notice...
我们被困在海洋中了
...we're stuck in the middle of the ocean on this couch?
我的意思是  又不会有巨大的船
I mean, it's not like a big gigantic ship...
突然冒出来营救我们
...is gonna come out of nowhere and save us--
我的天呐
My gosh!
快停下
Avast, mateys!
金属胡子  我以为你说我们是注定要失败的呢
Metal Beard, I thought you said we were a lost cause!
是啊
Ye are!
你没有听完我的故事吗
Did ye not hear me whole story...
关于这个愚蠢的行动
...circumscribing the folly of this whole enterprise?
好吧  在你大喊大叫的时候  想不听都难
Well, it's kind of hard not to hear when you're yelling everything.
你为什么又回来了
So why did you come back?
这应该就是双层沙发了吧
This be-doubled land couch.
我看到邪恶暴君的军队完全忽视了这个
I watched Lord Business' forces completely overlook it.
这就意味着我们需要更多像这样看起来无用的主意
Which means we need more ideas like it!
哦  多谢
Oh, thank you.
我们需要那些主意又蠢又笨
Ideas so dumb and bad...
以至于没人会想到这些有可能是有用的
...that no one would ever think they could possibly be useful.
还是谢谢你
Oh. Thank you.
那么  救世主  我们该怎么做
So, Special, what do we do?
额
Uh...
这样
Well...
有什么事是邪恶暴君认为建筑大师们肯定不会做的
...what's the last thing Lord Business expects MasterBuilders will do?
建造一艘宇宙飞船？
Build a spaceship?
杀鸡吗？
Kill a chicken?
嫁给棉花糖
Marry a marshmallow.
什么  就像这样：
Why, this:
你要如何让他们在农场?
How you gonna keep 'em down on the farm?
不  是遵守规则
No! It's follow the instructions.
-不喜欢那个    -听起来怪怪的
- Don't like that.   - Sounds weird.
不  听着  等等  你们听着
Now, listen. Wait, listen.
各位  你们都富有天赋  拥有丰富的想象力
Guys, you're all so talented and imaginative.
但你们却无法像个团队似的一起合作
But you can't work together as a team.
我只是一个建筑工人
I'm just a construction worker.
但当我有计划  而且大家一起合作的时候
But when I had a plan and we were all working together...
我们就可以建造一栋摩天大楼
...I mean, we could build a skyscraper.
你们都是建筑大师
Now, you're MasterBuilders.
想想如果你们合作的话会发生什么
Just imagine what could happen if you did that.
你们可以拯救这个世界
You could save the universe.
说得好  埃米特  说得好
Well said, Emmet. Well said.
真的吗？
Really?
小伙子  这确实是个好演讲
She be a fine speech there, laddie.
好
Okay
谁给我一些标签
Somebody get me some markers...
一些建筑用纸
...some construction paper...
和一些闪光胶
...and some glitter glue!
我把这个计划叫做
I call this:
"埃米特计划进入奥坦塔
"Emmet's plan to get inside the Tower...
把反抗法宝放到克拉格上
...put the Piece of Resistance on the Kragle...
以拯救世界"
...and save the world."
我在那座城市建了上百座像奥坦塔的建筑
I've built a hundred just like them back in the city.
只要我们能进得去  我就能知道空气管道和线路的位置
If we can just get in, I know where the air ducts and wiring are located.
我能把我们带到奥坦塔的任何地方
I can get us anywhere.
拿我们该怎么进入奥坦塔呢
How will we get inside?
通过一艘宇宙飞船
In a spaceship.
-宇宙飞船  哈哈    -好主意  一艘蝙蝠宇宙飞船
- Spaceship! Ha, ha!   - Great idea. A Bat-Spaceship.
不  他们就等着我们开
No, they're expecting us to show up...
蝙蝠飞船  海盗飞船或彩虹飞船现身
...in a Bat-Spaceship, or a pirate spaceship or a rainbow-sparkle spaceship.
我觉得其中之一听着不错
One of those sounds awesome to me.
我的意见是建一艘
My idea is to build a spaceship...
和奥坦塔运输飞船一模一样的宇宙飞船
...that's exactly like all the other Octan delivery spaceships.
所以不是要我正在造的这种特殊飞船？
So not the special spaceship that I'm building for all of you right now?
对不起  本尼  或许下次需要
Sorry, Benny. Maybe next time.
你真是都要让我窒息了
Ooh, you're really letting the oxygen out of my tank here.
但是根据你指导手册
Yeah, but according to your precious instructions...
这艘飞船需要超光速引擎
...this ship needs a hyperdrive.
但我们却没有那个
We don't have that part.
也许我们可以找一个
Maybe we could find one!
你想得美  你当宇宙飞船会凭空出现在我们面前吗
What do you think, a spaceship is just gonna appear out of the blue?
这是在逗我嘛
Are you kidding me?
宇宙飞船来了
The same thing!
丘巴卡
Chewie!
我们本来应该在去纳布星聚会的路上了
We're supposed to be halfway to Naboo for a sweet party!
这个超光速引擎却老是出故障
This hyperdrive keeps malfunctioning...
居然把我们带到这个垃圾星球来了
...taking us to loser systems like this.
梭罗船长  我们得走了
Captain Solo, we must go.
你知道如果我们不守时的话  我会变得多么烦燥不安
You know how perturbed I get if we are not punctual.
多罗德说得对  我们出发吧
The Droid's right. Let's roll.
等等  汉
Now hold on, Han.
这也许就是正确的星系
This might be the right galaxy after all.
因为我看到一个漂亮的女士了
Because I see a heavenly body.
喔哦  我已经有男朋友了  而且他很厉害的  对吧  亲爱的
Ooh, whoa, I have a boyfriend. And it is super serious. Right, babe?
-当然了    -对嘛
- Of course it's serious.   - Yeah!
-你的飞船上还有空位吗    -你干嘛呢  亲爱的
- Got room for just one dude?   - Whoa! Babe!
像你这么酷的人  当然有位置了
If he's a cool dude like you.
你想要抛弃我们
You're trying to bail on us!
我们有想要抛下你
I'm not trying to bail!
你都问他们飞船上是不是有空余的座位了
You asked them if you could go with them on their party ship!
那飞船上充满了享乐主义者
That thing is filled with bon vivants.
你现在说法语了？
You speak French now?
听着  亲爱的  要想我们的恋爱关系维持下去
Babe, look, if this relationship is ever gonna work between us...
任何时候我就得拥有选择
...I need to feel free to party...
和一群陌生人去参加派对的权利
...with a bunch of strangers whenever I feel like it.
你说什么
What?
亲爱的
Babe!
我会给你发短信的
I will text you.
兄弟  你哪弄来这么好的飞船的
Where'd you get that sweet space cape, brother?
现在是派对时间
It's party time!
亲爱的
Babe?
温斯黛  你是一个非常了不起的人
Wyldstyle, you're such an amazing person.
你知道吗  如果蝙蝠侠看不到这一点  那么他就...
And, you know, if Batman can't see that, then he's just--
他就和那些盲人一样
Well, he's just as blind as a guy...
瞎了眼
...whose eyes stopped working.
说句心里话
And I'm gonna tell you something:
蝙蝠侠是我见过的人里面最糟糕的
Batman is the worst person I've ever met.
-需要超光速引擎吗？    -不是吧
- Need a hyperdrive?   - No way.
-亲爱的    -我就知道  我就知道你不会离开的
- Babe!   - I knew it! I knew that.
你刚才真的骗到我了
You really had me there!
那几个人太傻了  他们会做的只是玩空间跳棋
Those guys were so lame. All they did was play space checkers.
另外  原来那个长头发的居然是个男的
Plus, it turns out the hairy one's a dude.
还有那个机器人  全都是男的
And the metal one too. All dudes.
但他们不会注意到他们的超光速引擎没了吗
But won't they notice their hyperdrive is missing?
快点  丘巴卡  发动超光速引擎
Come on, Chewie, hit the hyperdrive.
不用担心  他们不会有事的
Nah, they'll be fine.
让我们建一艘宇宙飞船
第1步：
Step one:
好了  我们需要一个四件套的红色部件
All right, we need a red four-piece unit over at the--
独角猫
Unikitty...
你应该要遵守规则  记得吗
you're supposed to follow the instructions, remember?
对不起
Sorry.
呃  这些规则让我神经过敏
Ugh, this gives me the jeebies.
我应该要...我做不到
What do I even--? I can't--!
好
Nice!
第2步：
Step two:
我们驾驶这艘飞船混入奥坦公司的飞船中
We pilot the ship to the service entrance...
这样我们就可以免除入口的危险
...so we can get past the dangerous...
这还挺酷的
...but also kind of cool...
激光门
...laser gate.
请出示证明
Space ID.
我有驾驶证的
I have a drive-on.
你们来这找谁
Who are you here to see?
你是来这看你的屁股的
I'm here to see Your Butt.
是姓"屁股"  名"你"吗  还是
Is that last name "Butt," first name "Your," or is it--?
哦  我的天呐
Oh, my gosh!
一击即中
First try!
第3步：我们闯进邪恶暴君的办公室
Step three." We break into Lord Business' office...
然后我们会掠夺他收藏的宝物来伪装自己
...and we'll plunder his collection of relics for disguises.
第4步：
Step four:
本尼和金属胡子
Benny and Metal Beard...
偷偷潜入主控制室
will sneak their way into the master control room.
部门12的运动传感器被触发
Motion sensors triggered in Sector 12.
10-4跟我来
10-4.
你的想法和我一样吗
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
开始吧
Do it.
金属胡子  刚才这招太酷了
Metal Beard, that was awesome!
海盗第一定律：
First law of the sea...
永远别把你的屁股对着海盗的脸
...never place your rear end on a pirate's face.
一旦进入主控制室  他们就可以操控电脑
Once inside, they'll use their technical know-how...
来解除克拉格外围的防护盾
...to disable the Kragle shield.
我是计算机
I am the computer.
太帅了  能说话的计算机
Cool! Talking computer.
请解除防护盾系统
Please disable the shield systems.
如你所愿
Of course.
没有找到与你所说名字相符的电影
There are no movies in your area with that title.
第5步：
Step five:
维特鲁威注意警戒  以确保我们不会被跟踪
Vitruvius will provide lookout and make sure we're not being followed.
好的
Okay.
第6步：蝙蝠侠和独角猫进入会议室
Step six: Batman and Unikitty go into the boardroom...
去给邪恶暴君的计划做一些变动
...to make one last change to Lord Business' plan.
我提议我们将整个宇宙粘住  有谁有不同意见吗
I move that we freeze the universe. Can I get a second on that?
我有不同意见
I second.
我是布鲁斯·韦恩  韦恩集团的CEO
Bruce Wayne, CEO of Wayne Enterprises.
布鲁斯·韦恩：蝙蝠侠的真名
布鲁斯·韦恩  额  那是谁
Bruce Wayne? Uh, who's that?
听起来是个很酷的人
Sounds like a cool guy.
我们想要在你们公司做投资
We'd like to invest in your company.
你想用超级武器控制宇宙的计划听上去不错
Your weapon to control the universe sounds super sweet...
-我必须得说    -确实是的
-...I must say.   - It is, indeed, super sweet.
很好  这个计划的语音系统是什么样的
Cool. What kind of sound system does it have?
额  语音系统？  我们有个iPod Shuffle播放器
Uh, sound system? Well, I mean, we have an iPod Shuffle.
等等
Wait a second.
你是想说告诉我  你有个机器来控制宇宙
You're telling me you have a machine to control the universe...
但它却不能用来听环绕声吗
...and you can't listen to tunes in surround sound?
真是尴尬
Embarrassing.
额  我的意思是
Well, I mean...
我们会把音效系统完成  我要八英尺的扬声器
...we need to get that done. I want eight-foot speakers.
好主意
Great call.
是的  我要你们可以用你的手臂和双腿来拥抱扬声器
Yeah, I want speakers that you can hug with your arms and your legs...
然后去感受音乐的节奏
...and just feel the beat.
都听好了  我们需要给TAKOS设计出新的扬声器系统
Listen up! We need new instructions for a speaker system for the TAKOS.
我们不会帮你的
We'll never help.
你说什么我们就做什么  长官
Whatever you say, boss.
一旦扬声器做好后
Then once the instructions are printed...
我和温斯黛就会进入安放克拉格的房间
Wyldstyle and I will enter the Kragle room...
把克拉格放进反抗法宝
...place the thing on the other thing...
这样就可以拯救世界
...and save the universe.
等等  我没画那个  那是爆炸吗
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey, I didn't draw that. Is that me exploding?
额  我之前没有给你提过这点吗
Uh, I didn't mention that earlier?
当你将反抗法宝和克拉格重聚  就会有可能发生爆炸
When you reunite the Piece with the Kragle, it might explode?
你没提过  也有可能不是爆炸的  对吧？
No! But it might not, right?
当然  当然  我们继续说吧
Sure, sure, sure. Let's go with that.
全体人员注意  扬声器送过来了
Attention, everybody! Incoming speaker delivery!
你们两个是？
Who are you two?
我们是楼下的搬运工
We are transfers from downstairs.
-什么？    -再说一遍？
- What?   - Excuse me?
你这机器人的声音听起来像人类的声音一样糟糕
Your robot voice sounds an awful lot like a human voice.
你省省吧  我以前不是机器人
Give me a break. I've never been a robot before.
你什么意思啊  你一直是个机器人啊
What do you mean? You have always been a robot!
不  不  不 别听她的
No, no, no, do not listen to her.
你们的机器人序列号是什么
What are your robot serial numbers?
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
这是我最喜欢的歌
No way. This is my jam.
这也是我最喜欢的歌
This is also my jam.
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
当你成为团队的一部分  一切都是如此美好
Everything is cool When you're part of a team
-还需要多些和声    -我不想唱这首歌  我不是...
- Needs great harmonies.   - I don't want to sing the song. I'm not--
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
当你成为团队的一部分  一切都是如此美好
Everything is cool When you're part of a team
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
当我们实现梦想
When we're living our dream
快点  我们走
Quick, let's go.
一切妙不可言
Everything is awesome
我还以为你不喜欢那首歌呢
Hmm, I thought you didn't like that song.
我确实不喜欢
I don't.
嗯哼
Mm-hm.
我知道你表现的很强硬
I know you put on this tough act...
但我觉得你是刀子嘴豆腐心
...but I don't think you're as mean as you're trying to seem.
我一点也不刻薄  你到底再说什么
I'm not mean. What are you talking about?
我只是想说  你就像这样  "维特鲁威   他不是救世主
I'm just saying, you were all, "He's not The Special, Vitruvius.
他不可能会是救世主  这个人  你别和我开玩笑了"
He can't possibly be The Special. This guy? Are you kidding me?"
无论如何  我觉得那不是真正的你
Anyways, I don't think that's you.
真正的你  总之
The real you, anyway.
听着  埃米特
Look, Emmet.
我希望那个命中注定的人是我
I wanted it to be me, okay?
我希望自己成为救世主
I wanted to be The Special.
我知道这听上去很幼稚  只是...
And I know that sounds super mature. It's just...
自从我听说这个预言后  我就想成为这个天命所归的人
...ever since I heard the prophecy, I wanted to be the One.
在那个建筑工地里  我的判断是正确的
I was right there in that construction site...
我就站在反抗之宝的上方  然而
...right on top of it, and then...
最终那个命中注定的人却是你
...it turned out to be you.
在你说我是救世主的那个晚上
That night in the city, when you thought I was The Special...
你说我是最具天赋和最重要的人
...and you said I was talented and important...
那是我第一次被人这样夸奖
...that was the first time anyone had ever really told me that.
这也使得我下定决心  无论怎么做
And it made me wanna do everything I could...
我也要成为你说的那个人
...to be the guy you were talking about.
露西
Lucy.
什么
What?
露西才是我的真名
That was my real name.
你之前问过我  而我的答案是我叫
You asked earlier, and it's...
露西
...Lucy.
我喜欢这个名字
I really like that name.
嘿
Hey
-你们这两个失败者在讨论什么呢    -什么  哦  我们没说什么
- What are you two losers talking about?   - Huh? What? Oh, nothing.
我是过来帮你们的  我把独角猫留在那拖住他们了
Thought I'd help you guys. Left the weird cat thing to stall.
商业  商业  商业  数据
Business, business, business. Numbers.
-听的明白吗    -是的
- Is this working?   - Yes.
太好了
Yay!
坏警察在那
There's Bad Cop.
哦  丹尼少年  当风笛...
Oh, Danny boy, the pipes--
好了  等着我的信号
Okay. Wait for my signal.
祝你好运  埃米特
Good luck, Emmet.
露西
Lucy.
我想这就是永别了
I guess this might be goodbye.
我不喜欢说再见  我们还是把这叫做
I don't like goodbyes. Let's just call this:
"待会见"
"See you later, alligator."
英语中一句告别时的玩笑话  关键在于later和alligator尾音押韵
alligator没有意义  只是为了让整句话听起来较押韵而已
"待会见  短吻鳄"？
"See you later, alligator"?
一会见  鳄鱼
After a while, crocodile.
谁是露西
Who's Lucy?
蝙蝠侠  当我们进入这间房间时
Batman, when we get inside this room...
房间中会布满音频传感器
...there are gonna be audio sensors everywhere.
所以我们必须保持绝对的安静
We have to be really, really quiet.
别担心  我已经读过你那愚蠢的指南了  别再对我吼了
Don't worry, Dad, I read your dumb instructions. Stop yelling at me.
本尼  防护盾那边如何了
Benny, what's our status with the shield?
哦  耶  不  我这进行的很好
Oh, yeah, no, it's going great.
就是很好  为什么就没有人听我说话呢
It's just going great, if somebody would listen to me!
正在下载最新一集的《我的裤子在哪里》
Downloading latest episode of Where Are My Pants?
你从哪里得到的裤子  你知道我想要什么
Where are you getting "pants" from? You know what I want!
当风笛呼唤
The pipes are calling--
我是坏警察
Bad Cop.
你好  我是商业之王的助理
Hi, this is Lord Business' assistant.
他要你现在马上到他办公室见他
He would like you to come to his office immediately.
明白
Copy that.
-多谢    -不客气  先生
- Thanks.   - You are welcome, sir.
嘿  你是谁
Hey, who is that?
信号来了
That's the signal...
但是防护罩还没解除
...but the shield is still up.
那我们就即兴表演
We'll wing it.
这是个双关语
That's a bat pun.
嘘  本尼
Shh. Benny...
快解除防护罩
...disable the shield.
-解除防护罩    -就是现在
- Disable the shield.   - Now.
解除防护罩
Disable the shield.
-正在查找阿尔巴尼亚的餐馆    -什么？
- Searching for Albanian restaurants.   - What?
-不  我没有说过那个    -我听不明白你在说什么
- No! I never once said anything--!   - I don't understand what you mean.
解除防护罩
Disable the shield!
本尼  到底怎么了
Benny, what's going on?
解除防护罩  快啊
Disable the shield! Come on!
你在耍我吗
You are undermining me!
你想要我在哪句话加下划线
Which phrase would you like me to underline?
解除防护罩
Disable the shield!
让我试试
Let me try.
解除防护罩
Be ye disabling of yon shield.
防护罩解除中
Disabling shield.
不是吧？
What?
好了  3
Okay, in three...
...two...
...one.
动手吧
Let's do this.
露西
Lucy!
不
No!
哦  不是吧
Oh, man.
不要
Oh, no.
哦哦
Uh-oh.
在拐角处鬼鬼祟祟
Sneaking around the corner...
维特鲁威
Vitruvius.
看来你不小心闯进我的思维牢笼了
I see you've accidentally wandered into my Think Tank.
另外  我还抓到了你的一些朋友
And by the way, I found a few of your friends.
-我是指将他们所有人一网打尽了    -抱歉
- By which I mean all of them!   - Sorry!
干得好  坏警察
Acceptable work, Bad Cop.
多谢夸奖  长官
Thank you, sir.
小的们  给我把这个老头子
Robots, destroy this old man at once.
你刚刚说我老吗
Did you just call me "old"?
是的  你不服吗
Yeah. So what?
你知道吗  臭甲虫  我更喜欢你说我
Well, Junebug, I really prefer the word...
经验丰富
..."experienced"!
啊哈
Aha.
你看到了吗  埃米特
You see, Emmet?
一个堕落的灵魂是敌不过纯净的想象力的
A corrupted spirit is no match for the purity of imagina--
-哈哈哈    -维特鲁威
- Ha-ha-ha!   - Vitruvius!
不
No!
维特鲁威
Vitruvius.
我亲爱的埃米特  走近点
My sweet Emmet. Come closer.
有些关于预言的事情你得知道
You must know something about the prophecy.
我知道  我已经尽我所能了
I know, I'm doing my best...
但我...
...but I don't--
所谓的预言
The prophecy...
都是我瞎编出来的
I made it up.
什么？
What?
预言是我编出来的  它不是真的
I made it up. It's not true.
那就意味着我只是...
But that means I'm just--
我不是救世主？
I'm not The Special?
你一定要仔细听好了
You must listen.
我将要告诉你的
What I'm about to tell you...
将会改变历史的进程
...will change the course of history.
不
No.
这不是真的
嘿
Hey.
不再觉得自己与众不同了吧？
Not so special anymore, huh?
你猜怎么着
Well, guess what.
从来没有人说过我是与众不同的
No one ever told me I was special.
我也没有什么值得炫耀的奖杯
I never got a trophy just for showing up!
我也不是什么特殊的小雪花
I'm not some special little snowflake...
但即便是如此平凡的我
But as unspecial as I am...
你也还要比我平凡
...you are a thousand-billion times...
成千上万倍
...more unspecial than me.
小的们  把清零之剑给我拿来
Robots, bring me the Sword of Exact Zero.
是  商业之王
Yes, Lord Business.
你一定觉得很奇怪
It must be weird.
前一分钟  你还是这个世界上最与众不同的人
One minute, you're the most special person in the universe.
这会你却什么都不是
And the next minute, you're nobody.
我还在我的收藏室给它留了个好位置
Oh, I have a nice spot for this in my relic room.
哦  我的错
Uh-oh! My mistake!
不小心飞出去了
There it goes!
不
No!
再见  再也不见
Bye-bye forever!
好了  现在只剩下一件事还没做了
Well, I guess there's only one thing left to do!
发射克拉格
Release the Kragle!
-计算机    -遵命  长官
- Computer!   - Yes, sir.
设置倒计时100秒
Set the electric shocker to 100 Mississippi.
一般认为读1个mississippi的时间是1秒  故可以用来表示秒
好的
No problem.
-然后把所有人给终结了    -已经在进行中了
- Then terminate everyone.   - Already on it.
埃米特  你将会有足够的时间
Emmet, that should give you enough time...
来见证克拉格第一个终结的地方
...to witness the first location to be Kragled.
-你的家乡    -不
- Your hometown.   - No!
很不幸的告诉你  坏警察  我要把你留在这等死
Bad Cop, unfortunately, I'm gonna have to leave you here to die.
什么？  长官
What? Sir.
这无关私人恩怨
It's not personal.
只是例行公事罢了
It's just business.
商业之王的公事
Lord Business.
再见
Ciao.
将在99秒后
Beginning zapping termination...
开启消灭终结程序
...in 99 Mississippi...
98秒
...98 Mississippi...
97秒
97 Mississippi...
以此类推
...and so on.
所有人主意
Attention, everyone.
我是你们的总统
This is President Business.
大家好
Hello.
欢迎来到墨西哥卷饼星期二
Hi, welcome to Taco Tuesday!
不用担心这个大型的
Don't worry about this big black...
挡住太阳的庞然大物
...monolith thing that's blocking out the sun.
你们需要担心的是
What you need to worry about...
我接下来要问的这个问题
...is this question that I'm about to ask you:
有谁想要墨西哥卷饼
Who wants a taco?
我就知道你们都想要
Yeah! I know!
墨西哥卷饼  墨西哥卷饼  让我们疯狂起来吧
Tacos, tacos! We're going crazy! Yeah.
所有人注意
All right, everyone.
表现的像平常一样
Act normal.
完美
Perfect.
现在  所有人说"冻结"
Now, everybody say "Freeze!"
看来乱跑和尖叫才是正常的
So I guess running around and screaming is normal.
机器经理们  启动"自动造型"程序
Micro-managers, commence micro-management.
"自动造型"程序已启动
Commencing micro-management.
怎么回事  我动不了了
What's going on? I can't move!
求求你  求求你  没有谁来救救我们吗
Please, please! Won't somebody help us?
埃米特  你会像平常一样想出解决办法的  对吧
Emmet, you'll think of something, right? Like you always do.
你没听到维特鲁威说的吗
Didn't you hear him?
预言不过是他编造出来的
The prophecy's made-up.
我不是救世主
I'm not The Special.
曾经一度我甚至都觉得自己可能是救世主
And to think for a moment I thought I might be.
-埃米特    -谁在说话
- Emmet.   - Who said that?
我说的
I did.
我是维特鲁威的鬼魂
I am Ghost Vitruvius.
喔
Woo!
埃米特  先前你没让我把话说完
Emmet, you didn't let me finish earlier.
因为我死了
Because I died.
我之所以编造出这个预言
The reason I made up the prophecy...
是因为我知道  无论谁能找到反抗法宝
...was because I knew that whoever found the Piece...
都将成为救世主
...could become The Special.
因为想要与众不同的唯一条件
Because the only thing anyone needs to be special...
就是要相信你自己可以做到
...is to believe that you can be.
我知道这听起来可能很荒唐  但这是事实
I know that sounds like a cat poster, but it's true.
看看你在相信自己是救世主之后所做的事情
Look at what you did when you believed you were special.
你只需要更加相信自己
You just need to believe it some more.
但我怎么能在明知我自己不是救世主的时候
But how can I just decide to believe that I'm special...
还相信自己是救世主呢
...when I'm not?
因为世界的生死存亡就在此一举
Because the world depends on it.
消灭终结程序将在35秒后启动
Zapping termination in 35 Mississippi...
什么？
What?
34秒
...34 Mississippi...
33秒
...33 Mississippi...
32秒
...32 Mississippi...
31秒
...31 Mississippi...
30秒
...30 Mississippi...
29秒
...29 Mississippi...
28秒  27秒
...28 Mississippi, 27 Mississippi...
26秒
...26 Mississippi...
25秒
...25 Mississippi...
24秒
...24 Mississippi...
埃米特
Emmet!
你在干嘛
What are you--?
18秒
18 Mississippi...
17秒
...17 Mississippi...
-16秒    -露西
-...16 Mississippi...   - Lucy!
-15秒    -等等  你在干嘛
-...15 Mississippi...   - Wait! What are you--?
现在是你当英雄的时刻了
Now it's your turn to be the hero.
-13秒    -不
- 13 Mississippi...   - No!
12秒
12 Mississippi...
待会见
See you later, alligator.
不要
Don't!
不  埃米特
No, Emmet!
7秒
7 Mississippi...
6秒
6 Mississippi...
5秒
...5 Mississippi...
4秒
...4 Mississippi...
3秒
...3 Mississippi...
2秒
...2 Mississippi...
1秒
1 Mississippi...
0秒...程序出错
...0 Missi-- Error.
终结程序启动失败
Termination failure.
埃米特
Emmet!
不
No.
他...他救了我们
He... He saved us.
那我们现在该做什么
Well, what do we do now?
我们要看到这件事
There's gotta be a bright side...
好的一面
...here somewhere.
有人有什么好的主意吗
Does anyone have any ideas?
埃米特总有主意
Emmet had ideas.
这个世界就该多些像他这样的人
Arr, if only there were more people in the world like he.
或许有的
Maybe there are.
10秒后在楼下见我
Meet me downstairs in 10 seconds.
10秒后
亲爱的  我的裤子
Honey, where are my...
在哪里
...pant“?
-你好   -你猜怎么着
- Hi!   - Hey, guess what.
我们找到你的裤子了  这个系列可以结束了  本尼
Found your pants. Series is over. Benny...
现在马上进行全球直播
...send this out to everyone in the universe.
80年代的科技
1980-something technology?
这才对嘛
Now you're talking!
额  嘿  大家好
Uh... Ahem. Hey, everybody.
你们也许不认识我  但既然我在电视上  你们可以相信我
You don't know me, but I'm on TV, so you can trust me.
我知道现在的境况很糟糕
I know things seem kind of bad right now.
但现在有个解决的办法
But there is a way out of this.
这是埃米特
This is Emmet.
他和你们一样
And he was just like all of you.
似曾相识的大众脸
A face in the crowd...
和你们一样遵守着规则
...following the same instructions as you.
他过分的融入这个群体  以至于没有人重视他
He was so good at fitting in, no one ever saw him.
我欠你一个道歉
And I owe you an apology...
因为我曾经很鄙视像他这样的人
...because I used to look down on people like that.
我以前认为他们他们是一群
"I used to think they were followers...
没有思想或野心的追随者
...with no ideas or vision."
但结果证明埃米特拥有很棒的主意
Because it turns out Emmet had great ideas.
尽管这些主意看上去很奇怪
And even though they seemed weird...
和毫无意义
...and kind of pointless...
但他做的却是最能够
...they actually came closer...
拯救这个世界的方法
...than anyone else to saving the universe.
现在我们要完成他未完成的事业
And now we have to finish what he started...
建造任何你心里想的东西
...by making whatever weird thing pops into our heads.
你们的内心深处都有着很好的创造能力
All of you have the ability inside of you to be a groundbreaker.
我说的都是真的
And I mean literally!
打破地面
Break the ground!
掀开地板
Peel up the pieces...
拆除墙壁
...tear apart your walls!
建造出只有你们能做的东西
Build things only you could build.
来保护好自己
Defend yourselves.
我们必须和邪恶暴君战斗
We need to fight back against President Business'...
是他计划冻结我们
plans to freeze us!
今天绝不会是墨西哥卷饼星期二
Today will not be known as Taco Tuesday.
它将会以自由星期五的名义被铭记
It will be known as Freedom Friday!
但我们仍然处在星期二
But still on a Tuesday!
快停止直播
End of the line.
坏警察？
Bad Cop?
我觉得我的内心深处  仍然有个好警察
I hope there's still a Good Cop in me somewhere.
我会在这挡住他们  你们去阻止邪恶暴君吧
I'll hold these guys off. You go stop them. Yay!
说得好  但是我们该怎么过去呢
Great idea, but how will we get there?
小做一曲
T-minus one.
10  9  8
Ten, nine, eight...
-7  6    -我可以...
-...seven, six...   - I could, uh...
-5  4    -我可以建个...
-...five, four...   - I could build a...
3  2  1
...three, two, one.
我可以建一艘太空飞船
I could build a spaceship!
你们不打算拒绝吗
You're not gonna say no?
快建吧  虽然我不知道你叫什么
Build away, whatever your name is.
-太好了    -哈哈哈
- Whoa! Yay!   - Ha-ha-ha!
好的  宇宙飞船  宇宙飞船
Okay. Spaceship! Spaceship!
宇宙飞船
spaceship!
所有人注意  攻击那宇宙飞船
All units, attack that spaceship.
宇宙飞船
spaceship!
他去哪了
Where'd he go?
宇宙飞船
Spaceship!
温斯黛  快看
Wyldstyle, look...
是那些市民
...it's the citizens!
冲啊
Tallyho!
别忘了我们这些建筑大师
And don't forget us MasterBuilders.
发生什么事了
What is going on?
你快停止
You stop...
建造东西
...building that stuff!
快停下
Just stop it!
干得好
Great job!
这样或许真的能行
This might actually work.
是你的演讲激励了大家
'Twas your speech which roused this hearty crew.
如果埃米特看到这一幕
If only Emmet were here to see this.
他一定会说一些可爱的话  例如
He'd say something adorable like...
我会这么
Am I just gonna keep...
永远
...falling...
坠落吗
...forever?
这是另一个梦境吗
Is this another vision?
我在哪
Where am I?
那不是奥坦塔吗
Is that the Office Tower?
积木城堡
Bricksburg!
那是什么
What was that?
不  不  不
No, no, no.
不
No!
宇宙飞船  宇宙飞船  宇宙飞船
Spaceship, spaceship, spaceship!
这是什么样的世界啊
What in the world is that?
好可爱
It's adorable.
不  不  喔  不...
No. No. Whoa, no, no, no.
嘿  不要吃我  不要吃我
Hey, don't eat me. Don't eat me.
请你不要吃我
Do not eat me. Please.
你好  埃米特
Hi, Emmet.
额
Uh...
你好
Hi?
这就是传说中的
Is this The Man--?
上帝吗
The Man Upstairs?
怎么回事
What happened?
不  不  不  这简直是一场灾难
No, no, no, this is a disaster.
为什么  为什么  怎么回事
Why--? Why--? What? What?
这是怎么回事
What?
为什么龙在豪华公寓楼顶
Why is the dragon on top of the luxury condo development?
我只是在玩而已
But I was just playing--
听着  我知道对你来说有些难以理解
Look, I know it's hard to understand...
但这些是爸爸的东西
...but this is Dad's stuff, okay?
你眼前看到的这些
All of this that you see before you...
都是你父亲我的
...is all your father's.
这里的一切都是经过慎重考虑
And everything is thought-out very--
你到下面做什么
What did you do down here?
你把楼顶从这塔上卸下来了？
Did you take the top off of the tower?
这不过是个意外
It was an accident.
你是说你无意中
You accidentally...
熟练的
...expertly...
但又小心翼翼的把整个塔顶给卸了？
...carefully took the entire top off of that tower?
是的
Yes.
你该知道规矩  这些不只是玩具
You know the rules. This isn't a toy.
-额  但他们确实是的    -不
- Um, well, it kind of is.   - No.
实际上  这是一个高度精细的积木系统
Actually, it's a highly sophisticated interlocking brick system.
-但我们就是从玩具店买回来的    -确实是的
- But we bought it at the toy store.   - We did.
但我却是把它们当成大人的东西来摆弄的
But the way I'm using it makes it an adult thing.
这个盒子说了是给8-14岁的人玩的
The box for this one said ages 8 to 14.
那不过是个建议  他们必须写上这个
That's a suggestion. They have to put that on there.
你不能指望我不去玩这些玩具
You can't expect me to be able to resist playing with all this.
听着  圣诞节我送了很多玩具给你
Look, You have your stuff over near the Christmas decorations.
那些积木  随你怎么玩
All those bricks, you can build anything you want.
芬恩  我们来玩个小游戏  这游戏称作
Finn, we're gonna play a little game. It's called:
"把所有你玩过的东西恢复原样"
"Let's Put Everything Back the Way You Found it."
但是  爸爸  你不明白
But, Dad, you don't understand.
这样我才能把所有东西变成他们本身应有的样子
So I can make things the way they're supposed to be.
永久不变
Permanently.
更多的克拉格？
More Kragles?
让反叛到此为止吧
This rebellion ends right now.
启动
Commencing...
自动造型程序
...micro-management.
哦  不  不要
Oh, no. No!
哈哈  小心手雷
Ha, ha! Fire in the hole!
等等  发生什么事了
Wait, what's happening?
不  等等  不  我们在不断坠落  救命啊
No, wait! No, we're going down! Mayday!
不
No!
坚持住  杰夫  我们来救你了
Hold on, Jeff. We're coming for you!
不
No!
快停下
Stop!
哦  不
Oh, no!
啊  太多机器经理了
Arr, there be too many Micro-managers!
我现在拿着的是什么
What am I holding here?
-是一艘宇宙飞船    -不  这不过是大杂烩
-It's a battleship.   - No, it's a hodgepodge. That's what it is.
蝙蝠侠怎么在这
What's Batman doing on it?
这是什么  一个机器海盗？
What is this, a robot pirate?
停下  快停下  不要  快停下  停下
Stop! Stop it! No! Stop it! Stop!
你拿着那个建筑工人干嘛
You got glue all over that construction worker.
快点  把他给我
Here. Give that to me.
停下  停下  快停下
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
这些都是我的朋友们  不要  快停下
All of those are my friends! No, stop it!
我们是一个很棒的团队  朋友们
Ye were a hearty crew. But it be...
但一切都将结束
It be over.
不
No!
反抗法宝
The Piece of Resistance!
我还可以拯救他们
I can still save them!
让我们把这种粘性物质从这个建筑工人身上取下来
Let's get this gunk off this construction worker.
它不只是个建筑工人  爸爸  他是个英雄
He's not just a construction worker, Dad. He's the hero.
不  他不是
Nope, he's not.
他不过是一个普普通通
He is a ordinary, regular...
的建筑工人
...generic construction worker...
而且我得把他放到属于他的地方去
...and I need to put him back where he belongs.
我的雕刻刀在哪
Now, where is my X-Acto knife?
我必须拿到反抗法宝
I gotta get the Piece of Resistance.
如果我可以吸引到那个小造物主的注意
If I could get the attention of the smaller creature.
我得行动起来了
I gotta move.
雕刻刀跑哪去了
Where is that?
行动
Move!
好了
All right.
移动
Move!
现在  我没有移动
Now, I didn't move--
噢
OW.
-爸爸    -干嘛
- Uh, Dad?   - Yeah.
我好像看到雕刻刀新西兰中部那
I think I saw the X-Acto over there near Middle Zealand.
哦  太好了  多谢
Oh, great. Thank you.
不用客气
Welcome.
现在一切都得看你了  埃米特
It's up to you now, Emmet.
相信自己
Believe.
我知道我看起来像是张海报
I know that sounds like a cat poster...
但这是真的
...but it's true.
喔
Whoa!
抱歉  街道
Sorry, street.
吼吼
Ho-ho!
我现在可以洞穿万物
I can see everything.
哈哈
Ha, ha!
这鬼东西是什么
What the heck is this?
我是个建筑大师
I am a MasterBuilder.
派出我们所有的机器经理
Release every Micro-manager we have!
让我们抓住他  兄弟们
Let's get him, fellas!
嗨  各位
Hey, everyone!
-埃米特    -埃米特  加油
- Emmet!   - Emmet! Yay!
露西  我要冲进去了
Lucy, I'm going inside that thing.
放心吧  埃米特
You've got it, Emmet.
尝尝这个  哈哈
Take that! Ha, ha!
晚上好  过来
Good night! Come here!
我们会帮助你的  孩子
We'll help you out, kid.
这就是我的海盗风格
Here's how we do it pirate-style!
埃米特  就在那里
Yes! Emmet! That's it!
干掉他  小的们
Take him down, boys!
埃米特
Emmet!
保持乐观
Stay positive.
他们要把我活活撕裂了
They're tearing me apart!
保持乐观
Stay positive.
快点帮帮我
Come on!
哦  算了吧
Oh, forget it!
老虎不发威  你们当我是病猫啊
You all need to be more friendly!
埃米特  快走
Emmet, go!
快走  现在是你的...
Go! Now's your...
-机会    -她说的对
- ...chance!   - She's right!
-你能行的  孩子    -继续  冲进去
- You can do it, me laddie!   - Go on, kid. Get in there!
长官  有入侵者
Sir, we got an intrud--!
邪恶暴君
Lord Business.
你死而复生了？
Back from the dead, Brickowski?
但是一切都晚了
Well, you're too late!
小的们  抓住他
Skeletrons, get him!
该死  我动不了了
Argh! I can't move!
看到没  你的朋友们
You see, your friends...
哦  他们完蛋了
...oh, they're finished!
我的世界已经基本快完成了
My world is almost finished.
就只剩下了结了
The last thing I need to do is finish...
-你    -不  求求你住手
-...you.   - No, stop! Please!
如果你再过来  我就要发动我的秘密武器了
If you do one more thing, I'm gonna unleash my secret weapon.
你的秘密武器？
Your secret weapon?
是的  它就叫做
Yes, it's called:
救世主的力量
The Power of The Special.
听起来很蠢
That sounds dumb.
那好吧  它来了  我的秘密武器就是
All right, here it comes. My secret weapon...
这个
...is this.
这是什么  是太小了吗  我什么都没看到
What is that? Is it super small? I don't see anything.
是我的手  我希望我们能够携手
It's my hand. I want you to take it.
你希望我和你携手合作？
You want me to take your hand off?
不  我希望你能加入我们
No, I want you to join me.
看看这些人们建造的事物
Look at all of these things that people built.
你看到的或许是一团糟
You might see a mess...
正式  还有一堆奇怪、过时的东西
Exactly. And a bunch of weird, dorky stuff...
毁了我那些完美的事物
...that ruined my perfectly good stuff!
好吧  但我看到的是
Okay. What I see...
人们相互激励
...are people inspired by each other...
也被你所激励
...and by you.
人们通过你建造的东西
People taking what you made...
又建造出更多新的东西
...and making something new out of it.
芬恩  这些都是你做的吗
Finn, did you make all of this?
这些人都试图阻止商业之王
The people are trying to stop President Business...
使用克拉格
...from using the Kragle.
什么是克拉格？
What's the Kragle?
额  在那里
Um, it's in there.
在这？
In here?
严禁靠近
严禁触摸
别动手摸
商业之王就是坏人吧？
So President Business is the bad guy?
如果
If...
如果这个建筑师
If the construction guy...
要对商业之王说些什么
...said something to President Business...
他会说什么呢
...what would he say?
你
You...
你没必要去做
...don't have to be...
坏人
...the bad guy.
你
You...
是这个世界上最具天赋
...are the most talented...
最风趣
...most interesting...
以及最杰出的人
...and most extraordinary person in the universe.
而且你拥有令人惊艳的能力
And you are capable of amazing things...
因为你是救世主
...because you are The Special.
我也是
And so am I.
每个人都是
And so is everyone.
预言既是编造出来的
The prophecy is made-up...
也是真实的
...but it's also true.
因为它是关于我们所有人的
It's about all of us.
此时此刻  说的是你
Right now, it's about you.
而你
And you...
还可以
...still...
改变这一切
...can change everything.
哦  我们拥抱了
Oh, we got a hugger.
多加小心
Be careful.
因为我被告知  这有可能会发生爆炸
I have been told it might explode.
埃米特  多谢你
Emmet, thank you.
我只想让你知道  在我内心深处
And I just want you to know, from the bottom of my heart...
从这一刻起
...from this moment forward...
我郑重承诺  我再也不会
...I solemnly promise that I will never--
埃米特
Emmet!
嘿  各位  你们都还好吗
Hey, everyone! ls everyone okay?
露西在哪呢
Where's Lucy?
埃米特
Emmet!
露西
Lucy!
我们成功了
We did it.
哦  额  埃米特  等等
Oh. Uh, Emmet, wait.
蝙蝠侠  我有些事情得告诉你
Batman, there's something I need to say to you.
不  温斯黛
No. Wyldstyle--
我是说
I mean...
露西
...Lucy.
他才是你值得拥有的英雄
He's the hero you deserve.
-额    -多谢  蝙蝠侠
- Uh...   - Thanks, Batman.
在他变得能干之前  我就看好他了
I liked Emmet before it was cool.
我拿来了克拉格的解药
Whoops, I have the antidote for the Kragle.
这是怎么回事
How did that happen?
耶
Yay!
-克拉格的解药    -你看好了
- De-Kragler.   - Watch this.
-太好了    -妈妈  爸爸
- Yay!   - Oh, Mommy, Daddy.
你们没事了
You're okay!
-哦  我的儿子    -你好  妈妈  你好  爸爸
- Oh, son!   - Hi, Mom. Hi, Dad.
我们没事了  孩子  哈哈
We're okay, son. Ha, ha.
该吃晚饭了  今天是你们最喜欢的墨西哥卷饼星期二
Guys, time to come up for dinner. It's Taco Tuesday, your favorite.
-好的  亲爱的  我们马上上来    -是的  我们马上上去
- Okay, honey. We'll be up in a sec.   - Yeah, we'll be up in a sec!
-我得告诉你一些事    -什么？
- I gotta tell you something.   - What?
现在我允许你下来玩这些积木
Now that I'm letting you come down here and play...
猜猜还有谁可以下来和你一起玩
...guess who else gets to come down here and play'?
-谁？    -你妹妹
- Who?   - Your sister.
什么？
What?
好了  看起来世界又恢复和平了
Well, things sure have a way of working out smoothly.
我没说错吧  兄弟们
Am I right, GUYS?
什么？
What?
我们是来自Duplon星球的
We're from the Planet Duplon.
我们来这是为了消灭你
We are here to destroy you.
哦  不是吧
Oh, man.
全片完
后面还有"艺术家"蝙蝠侠的原创歌曲  有兴趣可以听听
--==本字幕由 HDWinG字幕组 荣誉出品==--
耶  这才是真正的音乐
Yes, this is real music.
黑暗  沉思
Dark, brooding...
有地位的
...important...
开拓性的
...groundbreaking.
让我看看歌词
Check out the lyrics.
黑暗
Darkness
无父无母
No parents
继续黑暗
Continued darkness
跟多的黑暗  明白了吗
More darkness. Get it?
光明的反面
The opposite of light
黑洞
Black hole
窗帘
Curtains drawn
在地下室中
In the basement
三更半夜
Middle of the night
一片漆黑
Blacked-out windows
其他地方遍是黑暗
Other places that are dark
黑色西装
Black suit
黑咖啡
Black coffee
听明白了吗  这还只是第一个版本
You get it. That's just the first verse.
黑暗
Darkness
无父无母
No parents
超级富豪
Super rich
使他变的更好
Kind of makes it better